<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-boston-marathon</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1897-04-20/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Boston+race+marathon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BOSTON Mass. April 10. The Marathon
games under the auspices of the lloston
Athletic association and patterned after the
games at Athens Greece In the spring of
189G were held this afternoon and were
witnessed by thousands of people. The
games Included a twenty-five mlle road race
from Ashland Mass. to Boston and athletic
games at Irvlngton oval while the road race
was In progress.
The winner of the road race was J. J.
McDermott of the Pastime Athletic club
of New York who covered the distance
In two hours fifty-five minutes and ten
seconds lowering by ten seconds the time
made In the twenty-five mlle race at
Athens.
Fifteen runners started from Ashland at
12:19 p. in. Their course lay through Nay-
tick Wellcsley and the Newtons to the
finishing point at Irvlngton oval. Dick
Grant Harvard's famous mile runner kept
with Grey of St. George's Athletic club of
New York as far as Wellcsley. At that
point McDermott came up and after a
sharp race with Grey to Newton Upper
Falls passed the latter who was forced
to drop to the rear. From Newton Upper
Falls to thd finish It was McDermott's race
and at the close he led tlio second man by
nearly a mile. Tlio first six to finish and
who are prize winners were
First. J. J. McDermott. Pastime Athletic
club New York two hours llfty-flvo min
utes and ten seconds second J J. Kiernan
St. Bartholomew's academy. New York
three hours two tnlnutt-x and two seconds
ends third. F. P. Thell of Jamaica Plain
three hours six minutes nnd two seconds
fourth. Hamilton Gray St. George's acad
emy New York three hours eleven mln
tea and thirty-seven seconds llfth H. It.
Eggleston. Pastime academy New York
three hours seventeen minutes and llfty
seconds sixth James Mason Star Ath
letic club three hours and thlrty-ono min-
ottcs.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1897-04-20/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Boston+race</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>GAPS OF GREECE
tfK -VCK EVENTS PATTERNED
AFTEH THE ATHENS COMPETI
TION, HELD AT BOSTON.
ROAD RACE THE FEATURE.
TIME MADE IN GREECE FOR THE
TWENTY-FIVE MILES
LOVVKRED.
fIRST NATIONAL, LEAGIE GAMES.
Huston Beaten on the Home Grounds
by a Margin of a. Single
Ron.
BOSTON, Mass., April 19.— Trie Mar
athon games, under the auspices of the
Boston Athletic association and pat
terned after the games at Athens,
Greece, in the spring of 1596, were held
this afternoon and were witnessed by
thousands of people. The games in
cluded a twenty-five mile road race
from Ashland, Mass., to Boston, and
athletic games at Irvington oval, while
the road race was in progress. The
winner of the road race was J. J. Mc-
Dermott, of the Pastime Athletic club,
of New York, who covered the distance
hi 2 hours, 55 minutes and 10 seconds,
lowering by ten seconds the time made
In the twenty-five mile race at Athens.
Fifteen runners started from A&amp;h
land at 12:19 p. m. Thair course lay
through Natick, Wellesley and the
rwwtons to the finishing point at Ir
ving-ton oval. Dick Grant, Harvai'd's
famous mile runner, kept with Gray, of
St. George's Athletic club, of New
York, as far as Wellesley. At that
point McDermott came up and after
a sharp race with Gray to Newton Up
per Falls passed the latter, who was
forced to drop to the rear. From New
ton Upper Falls to the finish it was
Hh»Dermott's race, and at the close he
led the second man by nearly a mile.
The first six to finish and who were
prize winners were: First, J. J. Mc-
Dermott, Pastime Athletic club, New
York, 2 hours 55 minutes 10 seconds;
Koond, J. J. Kiernan, St. Bartholo
mew's academy. New Tone, 3 hours 2
minutes 2 seconds; third, E. P. Thell,
of Jamaica Plains, 3 hours 6 minutes
2 seconds; fourth Hamilton Gray, St.
George's academy, New York; fifth,
H. L. Eggleston, Pastime academy,
INew York; sixth, James Mason, Star
Athletic club.
The games at the oval were deemed
as secondary in importance to the road
race. </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1897-04-20/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Boston+race</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Marathon Gam s
I Boston APril 9The Marathon games
under the auspices of
tlo uspleS ot the Boston
1 I Athletic association and patterned after I
pattre nier
I the games at Athens Greece In the
spring of 1S96 were held thisafternoon I I
r and were witnessed by thousands of pee
pie The games included 1 25mile road
trace from 4shland Mass to Boston and
athletic gamesat IrvIngton Oval while
the road race was Ir progress WhIe
tTh 1nof
of t
d
The winner of the road race was J J
McDermott of the Pastime Athletio
i club of New York who covered the dis
J I tance In two hours 5 minutes and 10 seconds
I onds lowering by ten seconds the time
made in the 25mile race at Athens tme
T J Klernan at Bartholomews
academy N Y was second and F P
Thpll of Jamacla Plains third
The games at the oval were deemed as
of secondary Importance to the road race a</text>
      </result>
       <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1898-04-20/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=Race+boston+marathon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MARATHON RACE DECIDED.
Four Men Beat the Record Made at
Athens Two Years Ago.
BOSTON. April 19.— Roy J. McDonald of
thf» Cambridge (Mass.) Athletic Associa
tion won the Boston Athletic Associa
tion's" Marathon ra.ce to-day, covering the
distance, twenty-five miles, in 2 hours and
40 minutes. H. Gray. St. George Athletic
Club. New York, was second, in 2 hours
and 45 minutes; R. A. McClennan, East
Boston Athletic Club, third, 2 hours and
4* minutes; J. A. McDermott, PastJme
Athletic Club, New York, fourth. 2
hours and f>4\ minutes.
Each of these four men beat the record
of 2 hours no minutes 20 seconds, for
twenty-five miles, made in the Olympic
games at Athens two years ago, as well
a.s the record for the course of to-day's
10. The race was started from
Ashland at 10:40 o'clock. There were
twenty-four men at the line when the
Blgnal was given.</text>
      </result>
       <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1908-04-20/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=marathon+boston+race</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>IY NKfRS BOY WON
MARATHON IN TIM
CLOSE TO RECORD
iT P Morrissey First in the
Boston Race and Hayes
of IA A C Second
4 YORK MEN IN FRONT
M J Ryan and Fred Lorz
Were Among the First
Seven to Finish
BOSTON April IT P Morrissey
H the Mercury A C Tinkers N Y
won the Marathon road race here today
I
day covering the twent five miles In 2
hours 25 minutes and 4115 seconds or I
1 minute and 1315 seconds behind the I
record established last year by Thomas
Longboat the famous Indian runner
John J Havrs of the IrishAmerican
A C of New York was second In
J330 and Robert A Fowler of Cam
bridge port A C was third In 23342
The next rour men finished as follows
Michael J Ryan IrishAmerican A C
Sew York 227 03 George Brown
Nashua Y M C A Nashua N II
274S Jam a J Lee Boston Athletic
A soclatlon Boston 22S34r Fred Dirz
lomwk A C New York 23220
Morrissey finished close to Longboat
In the race last year He IB yet In his
i teens and weigh about 140 pounds The
1 conditions under which the race waa
run place the winner in the front rank
of American longdistance runners The
I rac this year had an added impor
taice In that it was the offlcal trial for
the candidates for the team that will
I represent the United States In the Mar
athon run of the Olympic games in Eng
land In July The best men In addition
to winning the prizes offered annually
I also won the right to wear the Stars
and Stripes In competition with the most
famous runners of the world i
I 100 Runners In Line
I More than 100 of the best long distance
j runners In America faced the starter
at the Boston Athletic Association club
1 house at noon Before the pistol was
fired a light snow began to fall and a
cold wind from the northwest was at l
the runners backs The course how
ever was In very good condition j
Roy Welton of Lawrence Mass led
by about fifteen yards at the OraL mile
I The rest of the runners were well
strung out At Natlck Welton led by
nearly a half mile and was two minutes
ahead of the record Welton held this j
lead at eleven miles his time being I
6741 and he was nearly four minutes I
ahead of Longboats record Only
Fowler of the first five among the
winners wns In first bunch nt this time
I</text>
      </result>
         <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1908-11-28/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=Race+Marathon+Boston</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>iLondon Marathon there v ns so much sympathy for Dorando because he
I
Icamo so near winning and collapsed after taking what looked like a per
fectly safe lend and there was BO much of pride In little Johnny Hayes the
L L u
looy wno passed me otners nuu
right on the Job when Dorando tell
Dorando Is going to run against Long
i boat soon The place tor the race has
not been entirely decided upon but
many cities will want It and Dorando
will clear more probably than he did
5n Madison Square Garden the other
night
Longboat Is a marvel when he Is
right He appeared in running races
Irleht
only a little over two years ago an un
I known Indian trom a Canadian reserva
lion
Longboats First Race
Longboats first race was the Herald
race at Hamilton the home of Shcrrlng
j Marathon winner at Athens Longboat
i knew nothing about running then He
was Just naturally a good runner like
most of the Indians He appeared at
Hamilton In a striped bathing suit and
ran In It He wore heavy brogans He
had never seen running shoes and didnt
know euch things were worn But he
won easily and after that there were
j plenty of men to coach him and look
out for his Interests Longboat was
forced to quit after running about
twenty miles In the London Marathon
He was in poor shape
After Hayes had wona few weeks
afterthe Englishmen ran off a consola
tion Marathon to give some English
men a chance to show after Hayes had
I left the country and Dorando had
turned professional Longboat ran In
that and won In faster time than Hayes
j had made But the real Marathon was
run on a blistering hot day and the
tone that Longboat took was In cool
weather In spite of that fact Long
boat may be able to give Dorando a hot
time when they meet If the great In
dian Is In good shape He Is taller than
Dorando by a foot or so and has a
long easy stride that covers ground In
fine style
Dorando Is quite willing to run
Shrubb the English professional over
the Marathon distance but no shorter
route Shrubb who can trim the world
up to fifteen or sixteen miles says thai
about ten miles would suit him nicely
and that the Marathon Is a brutal test
and no race for a gentleman to run In
any case he refuses to talk business
with Dorando on anything but a ten
mile basis And perhaps he Is wise
Haies broKcnIuartcil over his de
teat says that he will go on and train
and will yet take Dorandos measure it
he finds another chance to meet him
The upshot of tho whole thing may bi
a grand professional Marathon run by
i Doranda Longboat Hayes and Shrubb
with possibly a few crack amateurs iikt
Tewanlma tIle Indian inUULiil tu join
tile money winning team
The most curious tiling hour It all Is
that here In America wu have ncn i
cared at all tor loiiKUigtrfncc tool races
thinking them wtai isomu lor the spec
tutors We have always held back our
enthusiasm for the bprlntB And lien
the Marathon a distuiiie of twentybls
miles und i j yards lias becoma the at
traction that draws real money
the next few months Hayes and Dorando ag I
gregating their shares of the gate receipts I
cleared 7000 the other night This la enough
to make many amateur athletes eyes stick I
out with envy Hayes got 5000 which Is
about as much as hed set In ten years at
the job he left when he went to England
But of course there was a peculiar sen
timent attached to the HayesDorando race
which will be entirely lacking.
Crowleys Ladder Step
Has Runners Guessing
Hod Carrier Uses His Gallop
Form in the Mara
thon Races
IM CROVLET vs Dorando Pletrl
JIM That would make a great race If
the athletic experts know anything
about Marathon running
While It is altogether out of the ques
tion owing to the fact that Crowley Is
an amateur and Dorando a pro a
comparison of their recent races Is In
teresting
Let us tako Dorando first He Is a
tried athlete of many Marathons a man
whohas competed against the greatest
distance runners In the world He has
everything that goes to make a steal
runnerspeed endurance a strong
heart and experience
Dornndos race against Haye was on
an Indoor track a distance of IS miles
as yards whIch he negotiated In lib
44m 3J25S The track was the fast
est ever built In the Garden and bank
ed enough to take any strain off the
runners It was a merrygoround
from beginning to end and nr mile
after mile was run It was beaten Into
a smooth path Then there was tle
cheering of his countrymen together
with the band that played the airs of
I
his native land All helped to urge him
on and give him conlidence Ills rival
was with him over the entire Journey
und each knew tile others pace
Now take the race won by Crowley
This young giant of the IrishAmerican
A C weighs clohe to ISO pounds and
incidentally this knocks the reasoning
that only tmall men make Marathon
runners Tills big boy had not the
careful advice of a graduate trainer I
He Is a hodcarrier and hap to work
al day and train at night when he
should be getting tho rest that Is so es
sential for a dlBtnnce man
Ills first race wan when he entered
the Yonkers larothan a year ago and
after lending his Held for nineteen
miles being two miles In front drank
a pitcher of Ice water nnd then col
lapsed and was unconscious for two
I hours lie joined the IrishAmerican
A C and entered In the live and
I ten mile rnuLs during the past spring
and this fall Hi hail a peculiar stride
and JCrnle Hertberg the clubs trainer
tola him to run on the ball of his foot
Instead of on his heels lie tried this
t und it gave him n sort of crouch He
could not be biuken from this gait and
It has often been remarked Crowley
runs as If he vus taking a hod up a
Columbia Oarsmen Expect to
Be Heard From Next Svrina
I
How Croley Trains for a Long
I Distance Race
ladder and was afraid to miss the
rungs
Well thats his stride and on Thurs
day ho proved that It was a good one
He covered 26 12 mJles over a
I
track that wan a sea or mud and as
slippery as Ice It was up hill and
down dale One of the hills on th
c urlile was a mile and a halt anA
with an SO per cent grade For 21 miles i
he travelled along rough roads und
then entered the Empire City Track to
finish the last four miles
j Every rocpgopr known what a race
I course Is like when muddy Crowley
shoesnot the light track shoes that
I were worn by Uorando but heavy I
I soled ones weighed two pounds with
i the mud that was stuck to them and to
his leusas It was splashed up In the heavy
going Notwithstanding thm tact Crow
I leys time was Ih 9m 16 25s Dorando I
ran about three Quarters of a mile fur
ther than Crowley In almost five min
utes less time while Crowley finished
his last mile over tiii muddy race
course In less than six minutes
Everything considered Dorandoa time
I was not as good aa Crowleyu and he
would have to perform much better to
I beat this sturdy novice</text>
      </result>
         <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1909-01-02/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Race+Boston+Marathon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>UNTRAINED MAN
WINS MARATHON;
BREAKS RECORD
GEORGE B. MILLER LOWERS
TIME FOR EVENT
WINNER ENTERS CONTEST BY
MERE CHANCE
Stanley of San Francisco Second in
Los Angeles-to.Venice Struggle,
Having Been Passed at
Fredericks
FINISH OFJ/IARATHON
Numbers. Name*.' Elapsed Time.
H. M. S.
-George B. Miller 1:41:00
10—Win. Stanley 1-42-45
22—M. L. White 1:44:30
6—G. W. Isaacs 1:45:00
17—Oliver Starr 1:52:30
19-—Charles Boscha ............1:53:45
27— H. L. Becker..... 1:54:15
3—Win. F. Durr. 1:55:30
B—Frank C. Kosenaur 1:66:00
26Rameses B. Swaar 2:00:45
11 O. Wenden 2:01:15
—Louis Conti 2:10:15
21—George Aird 2:11:45
16— S. Pentz.. 2:16:00
—Frank Musante no time
15Iri Schragr no time
I—Ralph R. Pearson no time
Joseph K. Korinek no time
—V. Newman no time
—Panl Reinld ......no time
31 Emmet Martin no time
Edward Deitrich dropped out
18—William E. Coe dropped out
POSITION AND TIME OF RUNNERS AT
WESTERN AVENUE
No. Name. Time.
15 —Schrag 9:58:05
10—Stanley 9:58:06
22—White 9:58:48
6—lsaacs .10:00:00
19—Boscha 10:01:01
12—Reinwald 10:01:15
4—Newman .10:02:00
17—Starr 10:02:58
14 —Miller 10:03:00
—Musante 10:03:48
9—Korinek 10:03:59
11Wenden 10:04:20
B—Rosenaur 10:04:51
3—Durr 10:04:56
31—-Martin 10:04:59
27—Becker 10:06:00
I—Pearson 10:06:00
26 —Swaar 10:06:30
21Alrd 10:07:00
30—Conti 10:07:32
16—Pcntz 10:08:00
POSITION AND TIME OF LEADERS AT
CITY LIMITS
15—Schrag 10:06:24
10—Stanley .10:06:25
22 —White 10:07:22
6—lsaacs 10:07:40
19—Boscha 10:08:20
—Starr 10:09:05
12—Reinwald 10:09:40
4—Newman 10:09:51
14—Miller 10:10:00
POSITION AND TIME OF LEADERS AT
NEW ROAD HOUSE
15—Schrag 1C: 31:15
10Stanley 10:31:16
6lsaacs 10:31:59
22—White 10:33:00
14—Miller 10:33:48
—Starr 10:33:50
—Boscha 10:40:42
POSITION AND TIME OF LEADERS AT
PALMS. 11 MILES FROM LOS
ANGELES
15—Schrag 10:41:40
10 —Stanley 10:41:41
6—lsaacs 10:42:09
22 —White 10:43:15
14 —Miller 10:53:00
Starr 10:53:09
19Boscha 10:54:20
POSITION AND TIME OF LEADERS AT
FREDERICKS, OCEAN PARK
CITY LIMITS
10—Stanley 11:05:20
14—Miller 11:06:00
—Isaacs 11:06:05
—White 11:06:59
17—Starr 11:07:15
15—Schragr 11:07:81
10Boscha 11:08:00
ANEW record in the history of
western athletics was made yes
terday by runners in the Los An
geles to Venice Marathon race, given
under the auspices of the Los Angeles
Athletic club.
The race is distinctly the classic
athletic event of the coast. Eleven of
the twenty-three racers participating
lowered the former record, and George
B. Miller, winner of yesterday's con
test, covered the distance of 15% miles
in 1 hour and 41 seconds, a record which
future runners will find it difficult to
lower.
Miller's success was a surprise to all,
as no one had selected him as a likely
winner, and his name did not appear
among those who had been picked by
enthusiasts as probable winners. In
fact, he had not expected to win, and
had entered the race only to see what
he could do.
Finishing strong at the tape, Miller
did not seem to be much tired. Clad
in his running clothes, he conversed
with admiring spectators, while others
who had participated were being helped
tj dressing rooms where medical as
sistance was rendered.
Miller is a carpenter and lives at 749
San Julien street, Los Angeles. He is
26 years old and married. It is by mere
chance he entered the race. He was
urged by W. Burness, his trainer an-i
a man of many years' experience in
racing circles, to compete. Burness
had observed the young man had shown
great endurance when they went into
the country for tramps over the hills,
and he urged him to enter the race.
Miller is not a runner, never had taken
part in a race and had been trained
for a month only. This training he
did after working- hours, for he had
been engaged regularly at his trade
up to the time of the race. He n^ver
had run more than ten miles at one
time previous to the contest of yester
day.
Miller did not want to enter the race
because he had no running shoes and
because he thought he had no chance
to win; but his trainer persisted and
so he listed his name, saying he would
"just try it and see if he could stay
with the runners for a few miles."
Surpasses Expectations
Many persons thought the former
record of 2:01:30, made by Edward
Dietrich in September, would be low
ered ten minutes in yesterday's con
test. A few even ventured to assert
they thought it would be lowered fif
teen minutes. No one was so opti
mistic 2« to suggest that twenty min
utes would be taken from the estab
lished record. Miller lowered the rec
or 1 twenty minutes and thirty seconds
surpassing the most liberal predic
tions.
Miller averaged 6 minutes and 45
seconds a mile for the entire distance
The first four runners averaged better
than 7 minutes a mile. Considering the
condition of the course and the dis
tance, this is a remarkable record. Five
minutes is not considered slow time for
a mile run on a cinder path, where
contestants use spiked running shoes.
Scene at Start and Along Route of Los Angeles-Venice Marathon
By this comparison it readily can be
seen the pace set by the leaders was a
difficult one to maintain.
Practically every man of the twen
ty-three who started, exterted his ut
most to the end. There were few mis
l ps and all but three of the con
testants covered the entire course to
V-nice. Some of the veteran runners
who thought they were certain to win
are somewhat disgruntled at having a
new man, without any records to his
credit, take away the laurels.
From beginning to end the race was
as manly an exhibition of sportsman
ship as ever has been witnessed on
this coast. There is but little doubt
that the Marathon race will become an
annual event and that runners from
every part of the United States will
come to take part in it. It will grow
in importance as an athletic contest
until it shall attract national and
worldwide attention and be looked for
ward to as an event of first importance
in long distance road racing.
Thousands of persons lined the
course of the race, both inside and
outside the city limits, to see the run
ners pass by. Every man was num
bered so he could be picked out by
those having one of the lists published
in the daily newspapers. A small
army of wheelmen followed the racers
for the entire distance, shouting words
of encouragement to favorites. Dozens
of automobiles, carrying friends of the
runners and officials of the course,
followed the contestants.
Thousands View Contest
The start was made at the Los An
geles Athletic club, at 534 South Spring
street, promptly at 9:35 o'clock, a. m.,
when R. A. Rowan, president of the
club, flred the starting gun. Hundreds
of persons blocked Spring street to see
the start, and some of the runners were
cheered by organized bands of their
friends. So numerous was the crowd
the runnei-s had difficulty in getting a
start, and there was much delay before
the contestants finally ran into theopen in front of the Hotel Hayward
and settled into their paces.
In less than five minutes the partici
pants had spread out for a distance
of several hundred yards. The dis
tance apart became greater as the
race progressed, and at the finish the
men were scattered widely along the
course.
Edward Dietrich, champion of the
last race and first winner of The Her
ald cup, began to breathe heavily a.t
Eleventh street, much to the conster
nation of the many persons who had
looked on him as a sure winner. If
there was any general favorite in the
race. Dietrich was that man, largely be
cause of his previous record. It was a
surprise to everyone to see him giv
ingl out at the first.
For some weeks the former cham
pion has been suffering with a severe
cold. He found at the beginning of
the race he could not breathe through
his nostrils, and his efforts to get
sufficient air through his mouth soon
told on him. He ian close to Isaacs
until Adams street was reached. It
was pure grit which carried him on
from that point. He gave up before
reaching Hoover street, his follower
draging him from the street and call
ing for medicnl assistance.
From Hoover to Western the con
testants were scattered over the entire
distance. Iri Schrag, bearing number
15, reached Western avenue in the lead,
and kept the first place until within
five miles of Venice. William Stanley,
number 10, the San Francisco walker,
held second place at Western avenue.
He kept close to the heels of Scrag, and
the two held the lead until they had
passed the Palms. Here Schrag was
forced to drop behind, and Stanley took
the lead, laughing and jesting with the
followers.
George W. Isaacs, the Los Angeles
Athlotic club runner and athlete, held
fourth place throughout the race and
finished fourth, Miller sprinting ahead
of him in the last few miles. Isaacs
ran a stubbornly fought, consistent race
AT THE STARTING LlNE—Finley
(below), running strong, in the lead ao
Fredericks. Up to this point the San
Francisco boy had shown no signs of
tiring. He waved his hand to the
photographer as he passed. Finley
finishing in distress. Miller finishing
strong. He held up his hands and
breasted the tape, and seemed sur=
prised when attendants insisted on
assisting him to a cot in the club
annex.
Bag:
from start to finish. He did not give
any heed to the followers and specta
tors, but gave his entire attention to
the race. He knew his pace and held
it throughout the contest. He made an
excellent showing against the more
experienced runners, who tried in vain
to distance him.
At the new roadhouse Isaacs passed
White, who had been holding third
place up to that time. He held his new
position until he passed the Palms. Be
tween the Palms and Fredericks Miller
forged ahead of him and Schrag
dropped behind him rapidly to the rear.
M. L. White set the pace for Isaacs
from Hoover street to a point beyond
the six-mile post, when Isaacs took the
lead away from him. White was fol
lowing him closely at Fredericks and
forged ahead in the final grueling
sprint through Venice.
Charles Boscha held fifth place dur
ing the first part of the race. Then his
weak left foot began to trouble him
and he was passed by White, Miller and
Starr at the eleven-mile point. At
Fredericks there were five men ahead
of him. It was by hard exertions that
he made his rebellious foot do duty un
til he crossed the finish line at Venice.
Boscha was in splendid condition, ex
cept for his foot, and he seemed a likely
winner. His race was consistent and
showed headwork as well as physical
ability.
Oliver Starr is another contestant
who ran with his head as well as his
feet. At Western avenue Starr held
eighth place and kept to his pace. Then
he gradually reached sixth place and
held it until he arrived at Fredericks,
when he advanced again to fifth place.
During the final sprint he was unable
to make any gain on his speedy oppo
nents. Starr was followed by an or
ganized bunch of supporters, each wear
ing a large paper star. The men fol
lowed on wheels and cheered on their
favorite, who made an excellent
showing.
Paul Reinwald, the veteran hill
climber, did not make the showing ex-pected of him. He lost his follower
early in the race and had to rely on
other men for water and attention. A
slight illness on the day before the race
probably contributed to his failure.
V. Newman, the T. M. C. A. runner,
made an excellent showing, although
in no condition for the race. He
weighed 175 pounds and was nearly 15
pounds overweight. Everyone who saw
him predicted he would not reach the
city limits. But he stayed in the race
until within sight of Venice, when his
feet could not withstand the pounding
any longer and he had to stop with
only a mile to the finish line.</text>
      </result>
       <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058394/1909-03-28/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=Race+Marathon+Boston</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Most Popular Athletic Event
Many Races Scheduled
11
i HE athlotlc world In this coun
suffering from a
try In surely
J T scvcro attack of marathon
Itls This disease Is now In
big
Its acute form In nearly every
been aro going to bo
city them have or
hold many long distance races In eov
J k oral cities In the coat Marathon clubs
have boon formed and weekly races
are held In act no athletic meet Is
j complete without a Marathon coat Mt
on tho program Tho revival of this
famous Greek classic was started In
when Johnny
last summer
tills country I
s 1 ny Hayes defeated Dorando Pletrl In
fI v London In tho famous Olympic event
and renewed Impetus was given the
movement when tho pair mot In New
Yorl last Thanksgiving eve Many
j I new stars have been discovered and
i
j now America Is In lino to take from
England tho events on which they have
i held a monopoly for many years long
distance running Within tho last few
i months wo have had all kinds of Mara
thons Ico skating canoeing rowing
I walking bicycling roller skating and
i ono real novel ono which was held
t I
aboard United States warship
1 All Star Race April 3
J
As n climax to this seasons pro
1 a fessional gamo an all star Marathon
raco hay been arranged that should
Bcttlo for a tlmo at leant tho cham
i
pionship of tho world This big event
1 Is to be held at the Polo grounds Now
1 I York April 3 Tho competitors In this
I contest will be Alfred Shrubb Eng
f lands great distance runner Tom
1 1
i Longboat tho Indian Pletrl Dorando
r tho Italian and Johnny Hayes tho
I t American Matt Maloney formerly of
1 Ireland but now of Now York and
I John Svanbcrc who recently arrived
In this country may also start In tho
I big race
t Tho meeting of tho sextet In tho final
I contest of tho year on the first Satur
day In April will bo tho big event of
a f the season
I
With such runners on tho track the
I
contest will bo almost as much one of
t I j headwork as of endurance It prom
I ises to bo tho most Interesting running
J contest tho world has over seen All
I of tho men will havo had experience
I
I nt tho distance and a masterful ex
t hibition of Jockeying Is sure to be seen
r
When Shrubb mot tho Indian It was
I the Englishmans first Marathon He
never had run farther than fifteen
I miles but at that dlstnnco ho Is prob
J I ably without a peer today
Shrubb has always been unablo to
I find a man In tho world barring Ap
I ploby of England who can glvo him a
t raco at ten or fifteen miles Ho has
been beating men In relays In this and
f other countries In fact his great
ability has kept him from making
much money Tho Longboat race was
i his first big paying match
j Tho Italian may be the least liked of
tho four as tho winner ot tho contest
owing to his propensity to uso bad
Judgment and run himself out before
the tlmo for the final sprint But Do
rando has learned a lot since his ar
rival In this country He showed great
I headwork In his last raco with Hayes
Despite tho fact that ho has been
cast In the shade owing to hiD two
i defeats by Dorando Johnny Hayes
Ftlll has any numbor of admirers who
think ho can defeat tho Italian not
Indoors but out In tho open air They
claim tho Inhaling of tho smoo and
dust In the recent raco with Dorando
I Intcrfcrred greatly with his breathing
apparatus
Tho Indian will undoubtedly bo tho
favorite for tho big event Ho has
been running In superb form during
tho winter and his two easy victories
over Dorando and the ono over Shrubb
have mado him look Invincible to
many
Boston Run April 19
Many amateur races aro scheduled to
bo held In tho near future The first
of these to take placo Is tho Boston
amateur event April 10 This race Is
nn annual event and Is always held on
Patriots day All of tho countrys best
amateurs aro entered In this classic
r and a good rnco should icnult It ins
In thin event that Tom Longboat now
tho champion professional Marathon
I
runner mado tho fastest tlmo ever re
corded over the full distance 26 miles
i SS5 yards that of 2 hours 22 minutes
Owing to some technicality the tlmo
was not accepted by tho Amateur Ath
letic association Preparations aro
well under way to make tho run the
most successful over held In that sec
i tion
A novel Idea will bo Introduced In
that electric drays will follow tho run
ners ready to pick up the men In tho
event of their succumbing to tho pace
St Louis Is busy making arrange
ments for Us
annual Marathon race
which Is scheduled for May 1 All the
prominent western long distance men
have promised to enter and tho com
mittee Is attempting to Eecuro the en
tries of prominent runners of tho east
I Sidney Hatch who has won tho event
for tho last two years Alex Thlebcau
of Chicago and Joseph Forshaw of St
I Louis have expressed their Intentions
I of competing
All Southern Event
I An all southern Marathon open to
any amateur In tho oouth Is to bo a
I
feature of tho triHtato fair In Mem I
phis Tenn next fall and It will be tho
I
crowning event of an elaborate pro
gram of athletic features which It Is I
hoped will attract tho cream of the I
amateur talent of the entire Dixieland
Tho all southern Is to be for ama
teurs and Its management will be In I
trusted to Professor J Louis Day of
tho Memphis Y M C A Invitations
will be cent to all amateur athletic as
sociations In Kentucky Tennessee
Georgia Alabama Mississippi Arkan
sas Louisiana Texas Florida Virginia
and the Carolinas Colleges and Y M
C AB will be urged to enter repre
sentatives In tho race A handsome
trophy probably n 250 cup will bo
awarded tho winner which will carry
with It championship of tho south
History Marathon Running
Thirteen years ago tho first of the
modern Olympiads was held In Athens
Greece The first three men to finish In
the Marathon were Greeks Louis tho
winner was greeted h a shout that
roechoed for miles around tho sta
dium Thousands of foreigners who
wore represented at that International
meet acclaimed Louis a hero It seem
ed proper that a Greek should win
that classic event the Marathon run
And when two other Greeks followed
Louis across tho line In tho stadium It
seemed to bo definitely bottled that In
Greece the greatest distance runners In
the world were bred
It was tho revival ot the Olympic
games at Athens In 1806 that created
jthe recrudescence of Interest In long
distance running as a competitive
I sport Truo tho English revived tho
most ancient and most simple of ath
letic sports about seventy years ago
Prizes were offered In competitions all
over the country and from that time
until tho present England has pro
duced moro good runners than any
other country Tho Englishmen go In
moro for distance running than for
fast work as can bo easily seen from
closo scrutiny qf all tho records for
distance from ono mile up to twenty
After the 1S9G event In Athens tho
world evinced an Interest In Marathon
running Many countries participating
In tho Olympiad took up this branch of
sport and In these countries a new
generation of runners was born Prior
to this tlmo no ono In tho United
Statni offered prizes for men doing the
Marathon distance of 20 miles 355
yards Now tho Marathon Is tho most
talked of Taco In tho world
</text>
      </result>
       <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1909-05-02/ed-1/?sp=44&amp;q=Race+Marathon+Boston</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE MARATHON ARATfioIt1s ARATfioIt1sPOPULAR lS lSPOPULAR
POPULAR RACE RACEFA FAB FABOlympic AD ADOlympic J JOlympic
Olympic EentHas Event Has SuddenlySprungInto Suddenly SriddenlySprnngInto SuddenlySprunglnto
SprungInto Favor EaYorITS FavorITS FavorITS
ITS ORIGIN AND HISTORY HISTOEYrecian HISTORYGrecian BISTORYGrecian
Grecian Government Gov ment Established EstablishedContest EstablishedContest BtzLb1fshedContest
Contest in Jlemor Memory of offlonner Runner Who WhoCarried WhoCnrrled WhoCarried
Carried New of Battle nat Batt1e1ikc eJIlkc alike Mur Murphy 3Iurph 1ur 1urphy
phy ph Says Sz Tobody obod Under Twenty Twentyone Twentone TwentyOne
one Years Should Attempt Race RaceMARATHON Rac RaclrIARATHON Racet RaceMARATHON
FrobaMy aetaJag ddag hue bIIlIc aprons u m hi puo puolic pub publie
lic favor fa M a a aut a Marathea Mautb races racesFrom races1rom raceeFrlMa
From the vwy ry oW ij w wMIa e Oorajado Pietrithe Pietri PMtrIthe PhiLrthc
the plucky little Itaflaa fell unconacieuc unconacieucwlthta tlRCGlUdni tlRCGlUdniwtthla vuoudsuwithift
wlthta fifty feet t of the t ftttab P Mae Nethe ia iathe hithe
the last Olympic am Baee and Johany JohanyHayes JobmyHayes JohanyHayes
Hayes of o America Azaerh game quid nd piucfcy piucfcycaroe JhIckJcame 7 7caine
came ahmg aDd d won u the race did the theMarathon tileraees theMarathoo
Marathon races rc first st become a real pas pastime JIUtime pustAme
time te the world of aport Before that thatnothing tbatnotbiDg tbtnothing
nothing much was was thought of ofrCe6 MftradSon MftradSonraces Mradssiraces
races other her than the race bemg an event eventof EWeatof eventof
of the Olympic O yiiip4c games gam Bat that Hayee HayeeDoraaoo I8788 I8788DoraDd HtY HtYDorad
Doraaoo DoraDd flan ftId ntoh started the bait aroDwg aroDwgand at8I aromgzucl iIg iIgand
and now H seems as s though Marcthoe Matheraceo Marcthoeraces IIII IIIIraces
races are bemg run all over ov the country countrynot CIRIIIU7not eouutryzot
not only oa the cinder ciD er path but on o roller rollerskates 1IIerskates rollerEate
skates Eate aad M In dancing danci and aacleo waitziag waltihi aad aadso aadeOon
so eOon eOonSo en enSo tMl tMlSo
So far there t have already b been raced racedl1Qi la himere
13 l1Qi more Marathons than there have havebeen bftbeeR hvtbeen
been ma oaring durla the Jut ten t years 7oex The Theprincipal ritepr1Dctpal TheprinctpI
principal ones this year er w were re ifroee th be between be between between
tween Johnny Hayes Hfty and Dotaade Pietri Pietrithree PIebithree PlolrIthree
three diffarent events both turateg turla pre prefesaioa pcfEMioaal profese
fesaioa fEMioaal fese oni l steee neo the Jut bMOlymple Olympie race raceThe raceIbe raceThe
The other were betwee LoKgboat Lobot and andSbrubb andShrubb
Shrubb and Longboat oat and Dorando ad aadthe adthe andthe
the one which dedded the theoC champiocuhlp champiocuhlpof
of the world Id at New ew York which was waswon waswon wanwon
won by St Yves Hoar St St Yves te prac practically pract1tn7 ptacttefly
tically unknown and with limbs so small smallthat SIII8that saflthat
that it was considered a Joke to run nuts htm htmscahwst Ishesn1not
scahwst s 1ut such men ae Hayes Longboat LongboatShrabb Lugbee4Sbrubb1
Shrabb Sbrubb1 and Doraado He set a new e rec record leeord record
ord is i his race OB April X XWhere SoWJtere 3Where
d
The first Marathon race te this country countrywas countrywas countrywas
was held under uDder the auspices of the Bos Boston Boston Deston
ton Athletic Association on April 19 19 1SB7 1SB7the 1S91the SBT SBTthe
the year after the one held ht Greece GreeceJohn GreeceJohn GreecaJohn
John Graham athletic at tic director of the theBoston theBoston theBoston
Boston A A A A was the promoter of the therace therace therace
race The start s drt was made at Ashland AshlandMass Asft1 Asft1Mass AshlandMass
Mass and the finish nisk was at the Irving Irvington I IrvIg IrvIgton g gton
ton Oval 0vaI on Irvrngton street in Boston Bostonjust BoetOBJust Bostonlust
just twentyfive miles from the th start The Therace T1Ierace Therace
race was won by J J McDermott of the tbePastime thePs1me theatIme
Pastime atIme A A C Ca Ia I 25518 There were fif fifteen fttteen flfteen
teen starters and at tat time every everyone everyODewas everyonewas one oneteas
was thought crazy to attempt to ruB such sucha such1engthy suchcngthy
a lengthy course COU J J Keraan of New Newiork Nework Newyork
york ork was second s almost one hour be behind be bebind behind
hind McDermott McDcnnott lest nine ninexaads ninepruRds ninepunds
pruRds xaads in running the t e race raceIn raceIn raceIn
In 1SSS another one was attempted attemptedwhich attemptedthlch attemptednhlth
which was won by R R McDeneJd YcD neJd in inThe 242 242The 242The
The first New York Marathon race was washeld washeld washeld
held in New York City on September Septembermi JS JS1S87 1 11S27
1S87 The distance was twentyfive sties stiesand mflesand
and eighteen fisished oat of thirty en entries entries entries
tries J J 1 McDermott won the race ia lAi25
i25 35 5 25 H H Gray Gra was second secondjn secondJo
jn 2 the SOs s they ran twentyfive miles mU s sA sA
A
fa three tht li beers hd 3 an3 ana an ever Te ptdate pptodateMarathon ptdateMarathon p ate ateManrth
Marathon n 6 5 miles mUes38i uis 3S5 yards ya s is gIUR TUB In In2i Ini43
i43 2i the therec record rd made by y Hew HeRd St StYves Stv t tYves
Yves v SjLYves SL Yves also holds the t e record for fortwenty fortv fortweatyve
twenty tv tweatyve Yr1ive five miles by going same in i Mara Marathon farathoDs Marsthou
</text>
      </result>
       <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1909-05-08/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Boston+Race+marathon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MODERN MARATHONS
Frederic J. Haskin
mODAY on the course at the Polo
grounds, New York city, will be
run that mwl all atn
letie events, the international Mara
thon, this will be the greatest race of
its kind yet run. There is a purse of
$10,; I for Which long distance runners
from nil over the world will compete.
This is another proof of the prevalence
of Marathonltla, a disease that tirst
affected the Grwks nearly B0 years be
fore the beginning: of the Christian era.
and which has recently obtained a se
cure grip on Americans in a manner
without precedent in the annals of
amateur sport on this hemisphere.
Wh c n Johnny
i"' "VI""'* I"!"■'•'■"■".'- j' /.""''l
W d mMI
ran*' _^HMy 1
Hayes, a compara
tively lesser light In
athletic circle* ir
New York, carried
the Stars and
Stripes to victory
by winning the
Marathon in the re
newal of the an
cient Olympic
games In the Lon
don stadium in
1908, he not only
achieved everlast
ing glory for him
self, but caused a
renewal of interest
in lons distance
running the like of
which America has
never known.
Since the triumph
of Hayes nearly
every city in this
country has had
Marathon races.
While it was gen
erally conceded that
the team from the
F. J. Haskln
United States would score an over
whelming victor. In th matter of
points at the Olympiad, there was little
deep rooted confidence in the ability
of the Americans to carry off premier
honors in the most coveted race on the
program. For years field and track
sports of all sorts had been enjoying
a healthful development in this country,
but the improvement in the class or
long distance runners had been so
gradual that it was hardly considered
likely that any American would bo able
to successfully match strides with the
stars representing the nations that had
for cent ries made an especial effort
to foster long distance running.
In the hope of at least making a
creditable showing in the Marathon,
several Americans went to the murk.
The result Is history—Dorando failing
in sight of the goal, while Hayes sped
to victory. It was not until the eighties
that American trac* athletes pitted
themselves against the English, Myers
and Merrill In 1881 being pioneers in
the movement that had its culmination
in Hayes' achievement.
While one of the oldest events on the
athletic card, the Marathon race was
almost forgotten until the revival of
the ancient games In an International
athletic contest in Athens in 1896. These
contests were held in the restored sta
dium that had existed before 330 B. C,
toward whose first erection patriotic
citizens had contributed everything
from the gold of one to the thousand
yoke of oxen that another gave, and
whose seats were covered with marble
si bs by Herodius as a gift to the Pan
athenaic festival. Time and war and
forgetfulness had burled the stadium,
but in 1863 Tit was partially excavated,
and before these international contests
it had been restored to Its original de
sign, the underground chambers for the
athletes being the same as when first
used 2000 years before.
There the first athletic Marathon
race was run in memory of that his
toric day 2276 years before, when one
Phllippides, an Athenian soldier, ran
from the plains of Marathon to the
palace In Athens to tell the kins of
the victory of Miltiades and his Atheni
an and Platean freemen over the mer
cenaries of Dar'.us. The runner dropped
dead at the feet of his ruler, so history
and tradition assert. The city accord
ed him every civil and military honor,
his body lying in state In the capitol
for three days. Among the most an
cient pieces of sculpture is that of the
dying Marathon runner.
Marathon lies on the northeast const
of Attica. There the worshp of Apollo
had its first homo, and the district
'boasts that Hercules was first wor
shiped there. On the battlefield is a
mound, or soroa. where the 192 Athenian
dead were hurled nfter the battle. It
was from this historic place that the
course of a novel race was laid out in
1896. a course that followed as near
as history coul*. show the path taken
by Phlllppides, and measuring twenty
six miles and 385 yards. On the day
of the new Marathon the king of the
Greeks was to receive the runner as
did his predecessor, though this time
SO 000 people waited, knowing, 'for the
coming of many runners. Tl.~ fact that
the runner was Splros Louces, son of a
peasant of Attica, brought forth the
greatest applause of the whole contest,
and enthusiastic chroniclers aver that
the great shout rolled" off against Mount
Pentelllcus on the one side and Mount
Hymettus on another as did the joy
ous acclamations of tha people of
twenty-two centuries before.
Marathon races had little hold on
popularity after this until the London
event last year, though it was hoped
at the time of the Buffalo exposition
that the stadium erected there might
remain permanently and the Marathon
run then under such climatic difficul
ties would become a big event In future
athletics. Hayes 1 winning acted as an
inspiration to the athletes of America,
and clubmen, schoolboys and college
students Immediately took to distance
running, which, even now, is complete
ly overehadowlng in publl favor track
contests at shorter distances.
Johnny Hayes has written many ar
ticles on how to excel in the sport.
pointing out especially that the
important quality in a runner is dog^i il
persistence In training. Many of thn
greatest runners the world has ever
known first took up the sport for exer
cise alone, and it was on these pleasure
runs that they discovered that they
could attain a spe#d grreat enough to
enter races. In nearly every city
are at present clubs thatwere organ
ized to encourage Maraffion running.
Thousands" of men and boys who befor.j
last year never donned a running shoa
|are now undergoing especial courses in
developing wind and limb in the hope
of not only Improving their health but
becoming good athletes.

The usual mode of training is to jog
a couple of miles three times a week
on a pood road until the athlete or
his trainer feels that he Is sufficiently
developed to take longer distances,
when he commences to go ten or fif
teen miles without stopping. So numer
ous are the races at present that thera
is little need of a runner extending
himself to the limit. Few of the b«st
Marathon stars ever go the full dis
tance except in the races, although
they usually make it a point to run
twenty-five miles at least two or three
times before getting into actual com
petition.
In ihe Iden days, when a long dis
tance runner started his training he
usually denied himself every luxury
in order to work off surplus flesh, and,
as he thought, get in the very best con
dition. But all this has been changed
by the modern school of training, and
the almost universal rule at present is
to allow a man almost anything In
I the way of oating that does not disa
gree with him. It is Tie opinion
of most of the foremost trainers that
a man in training should abstain en
tirely from alcoholic liquors and to
bacco.

Perhaps the oldest of the annual
Marathons in this country Is the one
that has been conducted for the past
eleven years under the auspices of the
Boston Athletic association. It Is con
ceded the title of "American Marathon"
and is viewed each year by thousands
who line the course from beginlng to
end. The craze has also extended to
the navy, where several races have
been run aroand the decks of Uncle
Sam's men-of-war.
Since the London meet several of the
competitors in that race have met in
match contests, and ihe crowds that
have attended these events show beyond
a doubt that interest in the sport is in
no manner restricted to those who are
able to actually participate. Of these
post-Marathons the one that attract
ed the widest interest was the $10,000
Derby which was held in the polo
grounds, New York, last month, which
attracted about 30,000 spectators. In
this the first prize went to Henri St.
Yves, a Frenchman, who was supposed
to be completely outclassed by the for
midable field that included such men
as Hayes of America, Dorando the
Italian and Longboat the Indian. From
the outset St. Yves set a terrific pace
and literally ran his opponents off their
feet, winning by a liberal margin.
From a financial point of view this
race was one of the most successful
field and track affairs ever held in this
country.
One of the peculiar features of the
Marathon running is that the cleverest
men In the sport do not seem to suffer
from overparticlpatlon, a tendency that
must be closely guarded against In
other athletic activities. Dorando has
been in this country since early last
fall, and In that time he has on differ
ent occasions competed against the
best available talent in cities In all sec
tions. Despite the strain he has given
little indication of going "stale," but
on the other hand seeing to improve in
each successive performance. Hayes,
too, has given many exhibitions, and
has run several match races with first
class men, including Longboat the In
dian, who was one of the most promi
nent participants in the stadium tour
ney.
While Hayes has accumulated consid
erable money as the result of his vic
tory in London, it is said on good au
thority that Dorando has made more
than $20,000 since he reached these
shores several months ago—quits a
harvest for a. former pastr" taker in
a small town in the northern part of
Italy.
T.jre is a diversity of opinion among
medical authorities as to the probable
effect of running Marathon races. The
unanimity of opinion is that the sport
among undeveloped schoolboys or other
youngsters should be controlled so as
not to allow the untrained to run in
such a way as to make it too strenu
ous and result in permanent injury.
For centuries walking and running in
the open air have been considered
healthful, but when the distance has
become too long and the strain too
severe it has proved dangerous, as has
been shown by heart failure and even
death among tho runners. Among
trainers and even physicians who have
had opportunities to observe the con
dition of young boys the feeling is that
long races of distance exceeding a
mile should be avoided.
Rut for the thoroughly conditioned
athlete Marathons are not considered
harmful, and the present popularity of
the sport not only promises to become
permanent but should result In the de-^
velopment of long distance runners who
will be able to outclass the runners of
other countries. Among trainers and
other close followers of amateur and
even professional running there is a
feeling that the Marathon has come to
stay.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014248/1909-04-19/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=marathon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CRACK RUNNERS TO SETTLE
WORLD’S MARATHON TITLE,
New York, April IS.—Tlio world’s
Marathon championship will be decided
on the Polo grounds Saturday after
noon, May X, when the best men now
running will compete over the regular
Marathon distance of 26 miles 385 yards.
For some time the Marathon contests
have been confined to a few selected
runners, but the real claimants of the
title have not been seen in competi
tion. Of the men who have appeared
before the American public Henri St.
Yves, the speedy little Frenchman, is
the only one with an unbeaten record
on this side of the water, and the Polo
grounds race will definitely establish a
champion'.
The introduction of new blood will
serve to stimulate the public interest in
long distance running, while the addi
tion of several of the better known
men on this side will bring about the
long-sought opportunity of determining
who is the best Marathon runner in
the world.
So as to make the race a real cham
pionship affair invitations have been
sent out to Henri St. Yves, Dorando
Pietri, John J. Hayes, John Svanborg,
Edouard Cibot, Louis Orphee, Jerry
Simpson, Tom Longboat and Pat
White. This will bring together an ag
gregation of long distance talent never
before entered in an event.</text>
      </result>
            <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90052005/1916-08-13/ed-1/?sp=17&amp;q=marathon</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
            <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016244/1960-10-18/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=marathon</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
            <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014248/1909-08-27/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=marathon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Good Runners are Entered for Mara
'thon Race on Sept. 3.
Interest in the coming Marathon race
to be held at the Central Maine park
Friday, Sept. 3, is nt present very keen
and the people are assured of witness
ing a race such as is seen in other parts
of thq country. Some of the best run
ners have signified their intention of
coming.
Henri Renaud of Nashua, N. H
broke' into prominence as a. Marathon
runner by winning the Boston Mara
thon, held under the auspices of the
Boston Athletic Association on April
19 of this year. Bast Saturday he won
a 15-piile race from one of the best
Marathon runners in the country.
John Cullen of Narragansett Bier, R.
1., is a seasoned Marathon runner, and
bound to give a good account of him
self.
William Rozette of the Pastime Ath
letic Club of New York, although a
/oung boy, has been running for four
&gt;r five years, and is the winner of the
Rye Beach Marathon held in Boston
ast fall.
James W. O’Mara. formerly of the
r,ambridgeport gymnasium, and now of
Yonkers, N. Y., is another well known
Marathon runner. His most notable
win was the Brockton Marathon held
last October.
Edwin Ryder of Jamacia Plain, is
another young man well known in
Marathon circles and at 20 miles is con
sidered unbeatable.
William Weisman of the South Bos
ton Athletic Club and George Thomas
if Menden, Mass., are also among the
lumber. Many more are expected and
‘he event is being looked forward to
by all the people.</text>
      </result>
            <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88084272/1912-06-01/ed-1/?sp=13&amp;q=marathon</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-prohibition</id>
    <results>
     <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88084272/1917-08-02/ed-1/?sp=12&amp;q=constitutional+amendment</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PROHIBITION 160 APPLY FDR STUDENTS
BEFORE HOUSE COLLEGE TERM FARM ii PARK
Senate Resolution Refers
National Prohibition To
Vote of the States.
ashington, D. CU Aug. 2. The fate
i the senate resolution providing for
nationwide prohibition amendment
the constitution today rests with
me house. If the house approves by
two-thirds vote. the new amendment
tv ill then go to the states for ratifl
..tjon
The resolution passed the senate
yesterday by a vote of 5 to 20,
r ht more than the necessary two-
h irds and today home "dry leaders
;.-essed for its prompt consideration
i h re.
The only change made in the reso
I'j'ion as originally reported to the
viiate was the adoption of an amend
rxnt providing that the constitutional
amendment should be inoperative un
rus ratified by three-fourths of the
Mtes within six years from the date
of its submission.
TVt of He4utftR.
The proposed constitutional amend
nt is the first initiated by congress
-.ri' e that providing tor popular eiec-
on of I'm ted States senators, ap
.'cd in 191 1.
s adopted, the resoution, which
w as submitted by senator Morris
neppard, of Texas, Oemocrat. would
M.l the following article to the fed
i -Ml .-onstitution:
The manufacture, sale or trans
portation of intoxicating liquors with-
i. the importation thereof into, or
bo exportation thereof from, the
I in ted States, and all territory sub-
t in the jurisdiction thereof for
i evrrae purposes Is hereby prohib-
tr-i
Tru article shall be inoperative
nlf it shall nave been ratified as an
Miiendtnrnt to the constitution by the
i ilati,res of the several states, as
if tried in the constitution, within
sx. ears from the date of the sub
'maii thereof to th states by the
"ncresp.
The tongress shall have power to
-'i't. e this article by appropriate
-illation."
C'awnt- HaMi In Way.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066314/1917-08-01/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=prohibition+amendment</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Prohibition Amendment Is
Passed This Afternoon bv
65 to 20 Vote.
The Senate at 1:30 o'clock this aft
ernoon toted, Ci to 20, in faior of a
constitutional prohibition amendment.
The lote came after a long and heated
debate. The amendment Mill now fro
to the House, li passed by the
House, the amendment must be rati
fied iiltliiii the next six jears by two
thirds of the states to become a part
of the constitution.
l!y United Tress
WASHINGTON, August 1. The
Senate rejected, 62 to 4, the Hardwick
"bone dry" amendment to the Shep
pard prohibition amendment to the
Constitution. It would have prohib
ited the purchase or use of alcoholic
beverages.
The Senate voted, 56 to 23, to adopt
the Harding amendment providing
that the prohibition amendment to
the Constitution shall be inoperative
unless ratified by two-thirds of the
states within six years.
      </text>
      </result>
<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1917-08-02/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=prohibition+amendment</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Amendment Must Be
Passed by 36 States
in Six Years
Vote Is 65 to 20;
House Now to Act
Prohibitionists Claim Nec
essary Two-thirds in
Lower Chamber
l&gt; ti The TViNir.e Bu-eaii;
Washington, Aug. 1.? A six-year race
to make this a bone-dry country was
set going to-day, when the Senate by
a vote of ?i to 20 decided tt submit
a national prohibition amendment to
the states. This amendment must be
ratified by three-fourths of the states
within six years after it has been sub-:
mitted.
Tho six-year period w-,11 not begin
until the House of Representatives has
also passed by a two-thirds majority
the re.jolutior., but that this will be
done is not doubted by the most en
thusiastic wets. The highest hope of
the wets now to stave off the vote
:n the House until next session. The
House has until the expiration of the
present Congre??, on March I, l'Jl"&gt;, to
pass the amendment, so to nullify to
day's action in the Senate the wets
would have to stave off a vote in the
House until after that date.
Senators said 'o-night that this is the'
first time in the country's history that
a constitutional amendment. hns ever
had a time limit string to it. Thirty
six states. the necessary three-fourths
to ratify a constitutional amendment,
must have approved the bone-dry
amendment within six years following
the date the resolution is flnally passed
by both houses or it will fall to th"
grcund. If, six years after the House
nas passed the amendment adopted by
the Senate to-dav, only thirty-tive or
fewer states shali have approved it, all
the work done in getting the resolution
through I ongress and in getting those
thirty-nve legislatures to ratify it will
be lost.
Flght To Be Transferrcd
So the passage of the resolution bv
the House, which is eonceded to be
coraing, whethei this session or next,
will transfer the flght of the pro-
hibition forces to the state legi?-
iatures. The real battle will lie in a
tew states. It is probable, for in
stanre that but little atten'.ion will be
wasfd on such states as New York
and \'?w Jersey. The "drys" virtualiy
have twcnty-flve "sure" states states
which nrf now bone dry or nearly so,
Bt that they will only have to make an
upbill battle in eleven additional states
to ratify the amendment.
Ono or" the bijrgr?t surprises of the
day was not 'he vote on the final
adoption of the amendment, though
this was much larger than expected,
but the vote on r.n amendment by Sen?
ator Nevlar.ils. This would have made
the prohibition against -'distilled"
liquors, insiead of "intoxicating"
liquors, and would have saved light
wines and beer. It was defcated, 67 I
to 22.
Hy practically tha same vote tho
Senate refused to adopt a plan of Sen
Bttl P'nelan, of California, which would
have given the state legislatures the
right to pass either on a bone dry
amendn ent, or one prohibiting mereiy
diatilled liquors.
Senator Stone, of Missouri, one of
the prnnouncvl opponents of prohibi?
tion, trtatod the Scm.t" BBd fralleries
to another surpr.se. Waiting until the
clerk was reading the list of how the
Senators had voted. he \oted for the
r.m.endment. At once his col!eag-je,
Senator Reed. another pronouneed anti
prohibitioni-t, rushed to his desk.
After a hurried confab, he stood up
and addressed the Chair. He voted no.
This does not rcprcsent a conversion
on Mr. Stone's part, but mereiy his
idea 'hat the states should have the
right to determine the question.
How Senators Voted
Senators voting for the resolution
were:
Democrats Ashurst, Bankhrad. Berk
ham, Chamberlain, Fletcher. Gore,
Hollis, .lones, of New Mexico; Kend
rick, King, Kirhy, McKellar. Martin,
Mye'rs, Newlands, Overman, Owen, Fitt-!
man, Raasdtll, Roblnson, Saul.-tbury,,
Shafroth, Sheppard, Bhlolds, Simmons,
Smith, of Arizona; Smith, of Geor(-ia;
Smith, ?f South Carolmr.; Stone, Swan-
son Thompson, Trammell, Yardaman,
Walsh, Williams and Wolcott. Total.
M,
Republicans Borah, Brady. Colt,
Cummins. Curtis. Ferna'.d. Freling?
huysen, GrtBBB, Ha!e, Harding, John
son. of California; Jone of Washing?
ton; Kellogg. Kenyon. Knox. I.a Foll?
ette, McCnrabar, McNary, Nelson, New.
Norris, Paht, PoladtXttr, Sherman.
Smith. of Michigan; Smoot, Sterling,
Sutherland and Watson. Total, 2'.\
Total for, 65.
Senators opposing the resolution
were:
Pemoerats Broussard, Culoerson,
(Jerry. Hardwick, Hitchcock, Husting,
James, I.ewis, PhtltB, Pomi rene, Re"d
and I'nderwood. Total, 12.
Repubiicans Brandegee, Calder,,
France, Lodge, Penro?e, Wads.vorth,
Warren and W?eks Total, H.
Total against, 20.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1917-12-18/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=PROHIBITION+prohibition+amendment</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Nation
wide prohibition won in the Houae to
I day, and only the adjustment of a
I slight differenco in resolutiona between
the House and Senate now standa ia
the way of submitting to state legia
latures an amendment to th* Federal
Conatitutlon forbidding the manufect
1 ure, saic or importation of intoxicat
ing liquor for beverage purposes in the
United States or its terntones.
The vote in the House, taken after a
day of debate before crowded galleriea,
was :s:> to ISt, with the partiea diwid
1 ing almost evenly.
The margin for prohibition was juat
cight \otes more than the neceaaary
two-thirds of the membcrship of the
House required for adoption and twen
j ty-six more than two-thirds of thoae
voting.
Bryan Congratulated
Both wets ar.d drys had been predict
ing victory all day, and it was not
until the last few names had been
called that the anti-prohibition forees
conccded their defeat. When Speaker
Clarke announced the result the victora
were joined by the galleriea in auch a
demonstration aa ia rarely permitted
I in the House. Fonner Secretary Bryan,
an i.U?reeted apectator naarly ali day.
appeared on the floor and joined iu re
I ceiving congratulationa with Repre
sentative Webb, of North Carolina, who
had led the fight.
The resolution adoptcd by the Houae
.1 ntical with that passcd by the
Senate last August, cMJept that it givea
the states seveti years laatead of aix
in which to ratify the amendment. Sen?
ator Sheppard, author of the reeolu
tion, predicted to-night that the Senate
would accept the amendment tomorrow.
He raid he had assurances that the
seven-year period would bo approved
and that he did not believe a roll call
necessary.
The Preaident's aoproval ia not re?
quired and the state legislaUres ma*
BCt as soon aa they please after the
signaturea of the Yice-President and
Speaker C'lark have been attached to
the resolution.
"It will be aubmitted tomorrow aa
a hnstmas present to the American
people," aaid Senator Sheppard, "and
I believe it will be ratitied within
three years."
Every attempt to-day to put on
amendments to except light wines ani
beer wa3 beaten, aml III Iiemocrats
stood aligned with 137 FepublieanI
and four independents to win the flnal
victory for tha Prohibitioniat forees.
Prohibition Reaolution
Following is the reaolution aa adopt
ed:
"Resolved, by the Senate and
Houae of Repre?enta'ivei, That the
following mnendment to the Gon
stitution be, and hereby is, proposed
to the states, to become ralid as a
part of the Gonatitutori when rati?
tied by the legislature.i of the aev
aral states aa provided by the ton
stitution:
"Article Sectior. I. After one
year from the ratineatio'i <>f thia
article, the manufacture, salc or
transportation of intoxicating liquora
within, the importation thereof into.
or the e*portation thereo.' from the
United States and ail terntory aub
jecr. to the junsdiction thereof for
bevcrafje purpose il hereby prohib
"Scetica t The Congress and the
several states shall have concurrent
power to enforee thia a:';c!c by ap
propriate U x ^ition.
.-tion :i Tl shall be
Inoacrativc ui.icss it ahall have b?en
.1 as an aaacadmeal to the Con
stitution by the kgialatures of the
several states, as provided in the
i'oii?titution, within aevea yeara
from the date of the submisaion
hereof to the atates by the Con?
gress."
Webb Reglna Debate
The debate was begun, amid a round
of applauae from the Democratie aide,
by Caairmaa Webb of the Judiciary
Commlttca.
taaraacatativc Gard, of Ohio, lead
ing the oppoaition. declared the ameiid
inent propose i un invaeiea of the po
lire power of the atatci ar.d threatened
the unr.nimity ?f the American people
iu winning the war. The great bad>
of Amencans, he contended. want to
leave the whole malter juat aa It ia
now.
P.epre?entativc Gooper, of Ohio.. for
tho amendment, told the Houae:
"You iook into a hatbatid or a eoat
to m&gt;? if it beara a union label, but
you can look in vain into the whiskey
bottle for a union label."
Kepresentative Dyer, of Miaaoun,
opposirg it, declared the iaaue nothmg
more or leaa than whether Congreas
ahall atand by "Dinwiduie and the
AnU-Saloan Lengue, who think more
of thia isaue of the wet and the dry
than they do of the iaaue of whether
America or Germany ahall will thia
great war."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn95060914/1917-12-21/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=PROHIBITION+prohibition+amendment</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Prohibition Amendment Will
Be Submitted to States
for Ratification
The constitutional amendment
for national prohibition was car
ried successfully in the House of
Representatives Tuesday by a
vote of 282 to 128
The Senate completed con
gressional action on the amend
ment Wednesday by accepting
the resolution passed by the
House by a vote of 47 to 8
Following is the resolution as
adopted
Resolved by the Senate and
House of Representatives that
the following amendment to the
constitution be and hereby is
proposed to the states to become
valid as a part of the constitu
tion when ratified by the legis
latures of the several states as
provided by the constitution
Article 1 Section 1 After
one year from the ratification of
this article the manufacture sale
or transportation of intoxicating
liquors within the importation
thereof into or the exportation
thereof from the United States
and all territories subject to the
jurisdiction thereof for beverage
purpose is hereby prohibited
Section 2 The congress and
the several states shall have con
current power to enforce this
article by appropriate legislation
Section 3 This article shall
be inoperative unless it shall
have been ratified as an amend
ment to the constitution by the
legislatures of the several states
as provided in the constitution
within seven years from the date
of the submission hereof to the
states by the congress</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86069180/1917-12-22/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=PROHIBITION+prohibition+amendment</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>LEGISLATURE
Will Be tho First to Act On
New Prohibition Amend-
ment.
Leader of tho Drys Expected
to Begin Fight on
Tobacco,
Itenuulicnn Administration Not
Living. Up to Efficiency
Promises.
BIO FIRES ARE NOW-FREQUENT
Week after next tho Kentucky
Legislature will convene and the
eyes of tho country will be turned
this way, as this toody will bo the
first to act on the new prohibition
law just passed in Washington.
Those familiar with the affairs of
this State realize that tho coming
Legislature is practically committed
fo a prohibition amendment, but Its
action will toe heralded broadcast by
the Prohibitionists that Kentucky is
anxious to go into the dry column
and is more than half way ready
to adopt the constitutional amend
ment as submitted by Congress
and tho Senate. All of tho
Kentucky leaders of Democracy
from Gov. Stanley down are
In favor of submitting tho
question of State-wide prohibition tp
the people, and regardless of the
action of our .national bodies it Is
hoped that the people of Kentucky
will be given an opportunity to
register their opposition to this
narrow-minded and fanatical meas
ure. One consoling thought to the
people of this State will be that this
legislation marks the passing of the
hypocrites and fakers who have
made Frankfort their headquarters'
at every legislative session. The
usual figure-heads of this clan are
the down-and-out country preach
ers who; not able to secure a
church or congregation, use prohibi
tion as their means of making a
livelihood. They are assisted by
tho narrow-minded fanatics who
are insane on the subject, and last
but not least the wily politician, who
uses the Anti-saloon Leaguers and
the Prohibitionists to further his
political ends.
Kentucky has been cursed with
prohibition politics for tho past sev
eral years and it will toe a relief to
have tho question settled by the
people. There has hardly been a
Democratic political convention or
primary that Haly and Beckham
have not held the bugaboq prohibi
tion up to control the party, and
good men have been driven from
active service because they could
not seo their way clear to ,hark
back to tho days of Salem wlth
craft and Puritan fanaticism. In
their places sprung up unknown,
obscure and Incompetent Demo
cratic leaders, under the guise of
Forward Leaguers, who presumed
to dictato to tho party as a whole.
The passage of the prohibition
amendment means, back to ob
scurity for them, unless they Join
the anti-tobacco reformers, who
hope to follow in tho footsteps of
the Prohibitionists. In tho Re
publican party stirring old leaders
like Senator Bradley and ex-Go v.
Willson have been succeeded by the
Republican Prohibitionists like Hert,
O'Rear, Bruner and Morrow, all of
whom are advocates of down with
the demons rum, beer and wine,
and probably unintentional advo
cates of the soft drink dope syrups.
Thus tooth political parties .'will be
in tho humor for a house cleaning
after the prohibition question is
settled.</text>
      </result>
       <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066315/1919-01-16/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=ratification+prohibition+amendment</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NATIONAL PROHIBITION
CONCRETE FACT FOR U. S.
Nebraska, Home State of Bryan, is Thirty-Sixth
State to Ratify Amendment to FederalConsti
tution Which Drives Liquor Out From Atlan
tic to Pacific, From Canada to Gulf.
KILLS ISSUE FOR POLITICS
Goes Into Operation One Year From Today When
Every Saloon, Brewery, Distillery, Wine Shop
in the Nation Must Close andNew Sources of
Revenue Supply Our Treasury.
I!y United Press
MXCOLX, Nebraska, Jan. l(i. Xi'Iirnsk:!, the home state of Wil
liam .1. Hi-yiui, today ratified the fedral prohibition amendment,
beh'sr tl'i thirty-sixth and iinal state neceMiry under the federal
Constitution to art in making the amendmen', a part of the Constitu
tion. Ratification in the Xebraska legislature was completed at 10:2,
o'eloek this morning, wlien J he Senate concurred in a House resolu
tion passed earlier in the day.
The Senate two days ago ratified the amendment but the ratifi
cation resolution as passed by the House this morning was amended
and was returned to the Senate for concurrence.
The vote in the lower house was unanimous, iiinctv-ciglit repre
sentatives voting for the ratification. When the resolution was taken"
to the Senate for concurrence onlv one senator, Tanner of Omaha,
voted "Xo".
RATIFIES
Legislature for U.S. Prohibi
tion Amendment Farris
Votes "Yes".
Ily United Press.
JEFFERSON CITY. Jan. 1G. Mis
souri today ratified the federal prohi
bition amendment, only a few minutes
too late to be the deciding state. The
House concurred 104 to 3C after the
resolution had passed the Senate by a
vote of 22 to 10.
Senator Warren of Grundy County
moved the Senate adopt the resolution
and Harris of Columbia, dry leader,
seconded, and the motion carried.
Speeches favoring the resolution
were male by "Warren and Norman of
Stoddard County. Farris of Phelps
County concluded with a brief state
ment. He announced that he would
abide by the majority's decision and
would vote in favor of ratification. He
was wildly applauded.
Motion for the previous question
stopped debate and the Senate adopted
the resolution.
Missouri was the thirty-seventh
state ratifying the prohibition amend
ment. The Senate voted favorably at
10:30 o'clock this morning. The House
concurred at 11:12 o'clock.'
Hoth Houses in Wjoniing Vote "Ves".
Ily United Press.
CHEYENNE, Jan. 10. "Without con
testing the vote, both Houses of the
Wyoming legislature ratified the fed
eral prohibition amendment today.
New Mexico House Fall In Line.
Ji.v United Press.
SANTA FE, Jan. iC The New Mex
5co house of representatives ratified
the national prohibition amendment
today.
.Minnesota Semite Ratifies Also.
!y United Press.
ST. PAUL, Jan. 16. The Minnesota
Senate today ratified the national pro
hibition amendment.
Prohibi
tion became part of the basic law of
the United States today. Ratification
of the federal amendment by the Ne
braska legislature made that measure
the eighteent amendment to the fed
eral constitution.
All but a half dozen of the forty
eight states are expected to adopt the
amendment in the next few weeks, but
the action of Nebraska today gives the
ratification of thre-fourths of the
states, the number necessary to ad
minister John Barleycorn the k. o.
punch.
One year from today every saloon,
brewery, distillery and wine press in
the land must close its doors unless
as now seems likely, they are already
closed at that time by war prohibi
tion, which goes into effect next July
1, and stays until completion of de
mobilization. The amendment which outlaws li
quor in this country reads:
"Section 1. After one year from the
ratification of this article, the manu
facture, sale or transportation of In
toxicating liquor within, the importa
tion thereof into, or the exportation
thereof from the United States and all
territories subject to the jurisdiction
thereof for beverage purposes are
hereby prohibited.
"Section 2. The congress and sev
eral states have the concurrent power
to enforce this article by appropriate
legislation.
"Section 3. The article Rhall.be in
operative unless it shall have been rat
ified as an amendment to the consti
tution by the legislature of the sev
eral states as provided by the con
stitution within seven years of the
date of submission thereof to the states
by Congress.
This is the amendment adopted by
Congress December 18, 1917, and rati
fied by thirty-six states a little more
than a year later.
And these are some of the things
that the amendment will do:
Wipe out a stroke 236 distilleries;
992 breweries and over 300,000 saloons
and wholesale liquor establishments,
forcing thir employes to seek other
jobs.
Cut off from these persons annual
incomes totalling more than $70,000,
000 in pre-war times.
Cut off from the United States treas
ury a source of taxation counted upon
for an even billion dollars in their
first drafts in the new revenue bill
and millions in additional income to
state treasuries.
Remove the liquor question from na
tional, ate and city pontics for all
times and help increase city, state
and federal expense by decreasing law
violations.
The fight on liquor, triumphant to
day is as old as the constitution it
self. It raised its head early In the nine
teenth century and was looked upon
as "another crank notion."
But it gathered strength. Churches
took it up, doctors followed and then
came the organization of anti-liquor
societies, the anti-saloon league an1
others.
In the middle of the ninteenth cen
tury Maine went dry. Kansas fol
lowed. At the end of the Civil War
the little Wind of anfi-slave agitators,
who had won their fight, seriously
considered turning to the prohibition
battle. Their number included Wil
liam Lloyd Garrison and Poet Whit
tier. About nineteen hundred came the
"militant stage" in the person of Car-
FEIIERAL AMENDMENT
The prohibition amendment is
the eighteenth added to the fed
eral constitution.
Provisions or the eighteenth
amendment with the length of
time taken for ratification fol
lows. First ten amendments, known
as the "bill of rights" provided,
guarantees such as free speech,
ratified in nine months.
Eleventh amendment estab
lished soverignity of states;
ratified in four years.
Twelfth amendment, changed
method of presidential election;
ratified in one year.
Thirteenth amendment, pro
hibited slavery; ratified In
slightly less than a year.
Fourteenth amendment, made
negroes citizens; ratified in two
years.
Fifteenth amendment; en
franchised negroes on same ba
sis as white persons; ratified in
one year.
Sixteenth amendment, allowed
Congress to levy income tax;
ratified in three and a half
years.
Seventeenth amendment, pro
vided for popular election of
senators; ratified in slightly
less than year.
Eighteenth amendment, makes
country; ratified In one year,
four weeks.
About one hundred amend
ments have been proposed to
Congress, but only four besides
those ratified were submitted
to states.
rle Nation of Kansas, probably the
most picturesque figure the fight ever
developed.
Ten years later the crusade against
liquor had grown from the "ravings
of cranks" Snto an irresistable move
ment that swept the country.
But John Barleycorn will try to
stage a "come back."
Distillers are already planning a
fight on the amendment in the courts
on the ground that it was not adopted
by two-thirds of the whole Congress
and that the seven years limitalon in
it invalidates the measure.
The drys say they are confident that
neither of these contentions will hold
and on their side are preparing legis
lation carrying heavy penalties for
prohibition. A special agency in the
internal revenue bureau will be asked.
The thirty-six states which have:
ratified the federal dry amendment up
to today and the order in which the
ratification was made are as follows:
1. Mississippi, January 8, 1918
2. Virginia. January 11, 191S.
3. Kentucky. January 14, 1918.
4. North Dakota, January 25, 1918.
3. South Carolina. January 28,
NEW NATIONS FACE
PERIL, SAYS POWERS
Speaker Tells Dangers Con
v fronting Czechoslovaks,
Jugo-Slavs and Poles.
SEAPORTS ARE VITAL
Self Government Not Neces
sarily Independence, He
Points Out.
1918.
Maryland, February 13, 1918.
Montana, February 18, 1918.
Texas, March 4. 1918.
Delaware, March 18, 1918.
South Dakota, March 20, 1918.
Massachusetts, April 2, 1918.
Arizona, .May 24, 1918.
Georgia, June 26, 1918.
Louisiana. August 8, 1918.
Florida, November 27, 191S.
Michigan, January 3, 1919.
Ohio, January 7, 1919.
Oklahoma, January 7, 1919.
Idaho, January S. 1919.
Maine, January 8, 1919.
Tennessee, January 8, 1919.
West Virginia, January 9, 1919.
California, January 13, 1919.
Washington, January 13. 1919.
Alabama, January 14, 1919.
Arkansas. January 14, 1919.
Illinois, January 14. 1919.
Indiana, January 14, 1919.
Kansas, January 15, 1919.
North Carolina, January 14,
Colorado, January 15, 1919.
Oregon, January 15, 1919.
Utah, January 15, 1919.
Iowa, January 15, 1919.
New Hampshire, January
Nebraska, January 16, 1919
</text>
      </result>
          <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1919-10-28/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=volstead+act+prohibition</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Prohibition Enforcement
WASHINGTON, Oct. 27.?Following in the text of President Wilsons
message vetoing tlic Volstead war-time prohibition enforcement measure:
"To the House of Representatives: j
"I am returning without my signa?
ture IL R. 6810, 'an Act to prohibit
i intoxicating beverages, and to regu
late tho manufacture, production, use
and sale of high-proof spirits for
other than beverage purposes, and
to insure an ample supply of alcohol
and promote its use in scientific re?
search and in the development of
fuel, dye and other lawful industries.'
"The subject-matter treated in this
I measure deals with two distinct
I phases of the prohibition legislation.
One part of the act under considera?
tion seeks to enforce war-time pro?
hibition. The other provides for
the enforcement which -vas made
necessary by the adoption of the con?
stitutional amendment. I object to
and cannot approve that part of this
legislation with reference to war
time prohibition.
Objects Satisfied by Demobilization
"It has to do with the enforcement
of an act which was passed by rea?
son of the emergencies of the war
and whose objects have been satis?
fied in* the demobilization of the
army and navy, and whose repeal I
have already sought at the hands of
Congress. Where the purposes of
particular legislation arising out of
war emergency have been satisfied
sound public policy makes clear the
reason and necessity for repeal.
"It will not be difficult for Con-*
gres3 in considering this important
matter to separate these two ques?
tions and effectively to legislate re?
garding them, making the proper
distinction between temporary
causes which arose out of war-time
emergencies and those like the con?
stitutional amendment of prohibition
which is now part of the fundamen?
tal law of the country.
"In all matters having to do with
the personal habits and customs of
large numbers of our people we must,
be certain that the. established proc?
esses of legal change are followed.
In no other way can the salutary
obJ2Ct sought to be accomplished by
great reforms of this character be
made satisfactory and permanent.
Little Discussion Is Expected
Prospects are there will be little dis?
cussion. Senator Hitchcock, while he
seemed to believe there would be con?
siderable opposition to passing a bill
over the President's veto, said there
would be little time for its considers
tion. This represents how one grout?
of "wets" feel about it. On the other
land. Senator Underwood, who has
been one of the "wet" leaders evei
since prohibition has been an issue,
took the view there was no point in
holding up a law providing for the
enforcement of an act already on the
books.
"If the law is^on the books it should
be enforced," he said.
The only effect of the veto, so far a?
can be discovered to-nijht, is that in
New York and some other places where
the selling of 2% per cent beer was to
have been suspended at midnight to?
night, selling may continue at the same
risk as previously until the Senate bw
passed the bill over the veto. So that
forty-eight more hours of sellinz is the
prospect.
Veto Surprises Congress
This is bared on the comment of
Attorney General Palmer sent out to
newspaper men who wanted to know
the effect of the veto. He sent out
word that the situation would not be
changed by the veto, except that 2.75
beer could be sold in places where the
courts had held it to be legal.
The President's veto was one of the
greatest surprises he has given Con?
gress for a long time. The reasons
for his veto caused even more surprise
than the act of rejecting the bill when
members had a chance to read the
message.
The President virtually took the po?
sition that in combining war-time- en?
forcement with enforcement of the
constitutional amendment Congress was
attempting to enforce an act?war
time prohibition?of which he did not
approve and which ho had recom?
mended should be repealed. He ig?
nored the fact that Congress had re
jected his recommendation for the re?
peal of war-time prohibition by an
overwhelming vote In the House and
bf a vote o? 55 to 11 (five to one) in
the Senate.
Prospects for a "wet Christmas" art
as much up in the air as ever. No or.?
?s sure whether the ratification of the
peace treaty will be immediately fol?
lowed by a peace proclamation by the
President, which would be followed by
a lifting of war-time prohibition, or
whether it must wait until the tust
with Austria is ratified. </text>
      </result>
              <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066651/1919-10-30/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=prohibition+PROHIBITION</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Three hours after the President
sent his message to congress Monday,
vetoing the prohibition enforcement
bill, the House passed It over his veto
by a vote of 17 G to 55. The follow
ing day the Senate did the same
thing by a vote of 65 to 20, 8 more
than were needed.
The message vetoing the bill came
as a distinct surprise to members of
both the Senate anil the House, ns
no one had any intimation of what
action the president would take, and
It was believed it would become a
law without the president's signa
ture. When the message was receiv
ed great excitement broke loose in
the House and all other business was
dispensed with until a vote was had
on the bill, with the result as stated
above.
The President's message in vetoing
the bill follows:
"To the House of Representatives:
I am returning without my signature
H. B. GS10, 'An act to prohibit in
toxicating beverages, and to regulate
the manufacture, production, use
and sale of high proof spirits for oth
er than beverage purposes, and to in
sure an ample supply of alcohol and
promote its use in scientific research
and in the development of fuel, dye
and other lawful industries.'
"The subject matter treated in
this measure deals with two distinct
phases of of the prohibition legisla
tion. One part of the act provides
for the enforcement which was made
necessary by the adoption of the
constitutional amendment. I ob
ject to and cannot approve that part
of this legislation with reference to
war time prohibition.
"It has to do with the enforcement
of an act which was passed by reason
of the emergencies of the war and
whose objects have been satisfied In
the demobilization of the army and
navy and whose repeal I have already
sought at the hands of Congress.
Where the purpose of particular leg
islation arising out of the war has
been satisfied, sound public policy
makes clear the reason and necessity
for repeal.
It will not he difficult for Congress,
in considering this Important mat
ter, to separate these two questions
and effectively to legislate regarding
them; making the proper distinction
between temporary causes whic arose
out of war time emergencies and
those like the constitutional amend
ment of prohibition which is now a
part of the fundamental law of the
country.
"In all matters having to do with
the personal habits and customs of
large numbers of our people, we must
be certain that the established pro
cess of legal changes are followed.
In no other way can the salutary ob
ject sought be accomplished by
great reforms of this character be
made satisfactory and permanent.
WOODROW WILSON,"The White House,
'Oct. 27, 1919."</text>
      </result>
              <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064402/1920-01-24/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=prohibition+PROHIBITION</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PROHIBITION IS NOW
REALITY IN AMERICA
Became Effective at Midnight
e Friday, Jan. 17-Men and
Money to Enforce Law.
Washington.-Nationwide prohibi
tion by constitutional amendment--the
Y dream for years of those oppos(ed to
t- the sale of liquor-became effective
r- Friday at midnight, with the depart
ment of justice and the bureau of in
m ternal revenue, the two government
;e agencies intrusted with enforcement
;s of the new basic law, ready to take
p" drastic action against all violators.
n The final step in the work of en
forcing the new form of prohibition
was taken when Secretary Glass ap
proved finally the regulations to be ob
served by agents of the federal gov
ernment.
John F. Kramer, general proldbi
e. tion commissioner, announced that he
,e practically had completed selection of
y his corps of state commissioners and
r local agents and had been notified by
them that they would start at once en
t forcing the amendment as provided in
;e the Volstead enforcement act.
ig Commissioner Kramer said he had
's a staff of rearly 1,500 men ready for
d duty. About 300 of these will work un
d der the direction of the state prohi
"r bition enforcement officers, while the
is others will serve much as did internal
e revenue agents before wartime prohi
bition went into effect. In a few
states the state directors have not
been named, but Mr. Kramer had dele
gated their powers to internal revenue
officers, so the organization was re
garded as completed. Mr. Kramer's
bureau has $2,000,000 with which to
conduct its work uatil July 1.
The regulations under which Mr.
Kramer and his staff will operate com
prise one of the largest, as well as
I one of the most important documents
r ever issued by the treasury depart
ment. Its pages are replete with defi
b nite methods for application of the
at mendment and the Volstead enforce
ment act; the department's interpreta
tion of all provisions is set out plainly
r and unequivocally, and no room is con
sidered left for doubt as to what can
and can not be done in the future.</text>
      </result>
        <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1933-10-04/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=prohibition</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>VOTE NEARLY 2-1
Northern Counties Swell Ma
jorities Against National
and State Laws.
By the Associated Press.
RICHMOND, Va.. October 4—Vir
ginia made the score by States 32 to 0
today in favor of repeal of the eigh
teenth amendment.
The Old Dominion, one of the bul
warks of prohibition since 1914, turned
thumbs down yesterday on the amend
ment it had been the second to ratify
and at the same time recommended the
repeal of the Layman act, State dry
law.
Almost complete returns indicated
that every district in the State had
joined the repeal movement, with a ma
jority of the counties joining the cities
in opposition to the prohibition regime.
Repeal majorities were heaviest, how
ever, in the centers of population with
Richmond. Norfolk, Roanoke, Newport
News and Lynchburg piling up sub
stantial margins that ranged as high
as 4 to 1 and more.
Although belated returns from some
of the dry areas cut down the repeal
ratio slightly it was early apparent that
the anti-prohibitionists would win with
votes to spare.
Ui LAIC A.UI7U {JACCAAACLd AAA
the State reported, 92,000 ballots had
been tabulated for repeal of the eight
eenth amendment as against 51.530
cast against repeal in yesterday's refer
endum. With a slightly smaller number
of precincts reported, advocates cf a
State liquor control plan led State pro
bitionists, 86.381 to 47,431.
Repeal leaders, among them former
State Senator C. O'Ccnor Goolrick of
Fredericksburg, one of the State's out
i standing anti-prohibitionists, said the
j result was what they had expected.
NORTH VIRGINIA VOTE STRONG.
Arlington and Fairfax Counties Almost
3 to 1 for Repeal.
BY LESTER N. IN'SKEEP.
The Northern Virginia counties, ad
jacent to the District of Columbia, did
much to swell the vote with which Vir- I
ginia yesterday ratified the twenty-first
amendment to the Constitution of the
United States, repealing the eighteenth
amendment. These counties also over
whelmingly expressed themselves as de
I siring abolition of the State prohibition
law and substitution of a plan of liquor
control.
While the State voted for repeal of
both the national and State prohibition
laws, the Northern Virginia counties
built up a majority of something more
than 3 to 1. Arlington and Fairfax
Counties voted almost 3 to 1 each, Cul
peper County, 3 to 1: Loudon County,
2 to 1, and Fauquier County, 5 to 1.
The success of the repeal movement
in the Northern Virginia area was at
tributed today by Charles Pickett, re
peal chairman of the eighth district,
largely to the work of the women, who.
he said, had labored tirelessly to rid
the State of its dry law in an effort
to promote real temperance.
Pickett also' said that he was im
pressed by the sincerity of the many
people who never took a drink and
i never expected to. who worked for re
peal because of their conviction that
prohibition has been a failure.
It was indicated today that consid
erable opposition might be built up
here to the proposed dispensary sys
tem of selling liquor. This is based
upon the Quebec plan, where hard
liquors are sold by the State, and many
fear that such a system In Virginia
might build up another political ring,
since all persons engaged in the sale
of liquors would be State employes.
IvlInrlAn Pnllntr Vntf.
Arlington County, which had local
sption prior to the passage of the State
prohibition law in 1916, yesterday voted
both for national and State repeal by
a margin of nearly 3 to 1.
While predictions had been made In
many other Northern Virginia coun
ties as to the margin whicn would be
enjoyed by repeal advocates. Arlington
County had been counted as extremely
uncertain. Repealists had expected the
county to go wet, but few had esti
mated victory by more than 2 to 1.
When finally counted, the vote stood:
For repeal, 1,909; against, 786; for
State control, 1.887; for continuation
of State prohibition, 783.
The total vote cast yesterday also
exceeded expectations, most of those
familiar with the situation having esti
mated that not more than 2,000 of the
qualified voters would cast their bal
lots. Actually, however, there were a
total of 2.695 voting on national repeal
and 2,670 on State control.
The vote by precincts in Arlington
County was as follows:
Arlington—For repeal. 261; against,
99; for State control, 242; for continu
ation of State prohibition, 107.
Ballston—Repeal, 193; against, 80;
State control, 197; State prohibition, 72.
Came—Repeal. 170; against, 53;
State control, 166; State prohibition, 54.
Cherrydale—Repeal, 190; against, 90;
State control, 215; State prohibition, 73.
Clarendon No. 1—Repeal, 158; against,
84; State control, 158; State prohibi
tion, 83.
Clarendon No. 2—Repeal, 250;
against. 114; State control, 242; State
prohibition, 122.
East Falls Church—Repeal, 126;
against. 48; State control, 131; State
prohibition. 44.
Glen Carlyn—ReDcal. 38: against, 18;
State control, 38: State p-ohibition, 18.
Lyon Park—Repeal. 192; against. 68;
State control. 186. State prohibition, 70.
Rosslyn—Repeal. 176; against. 72;
State control. 165; State prohibition, 76.
Virginia Highlands Repeal, 155;
against, 60; State control, 147; State
prohibition, 64.
Fairfax County Vote.
Following Is the Fairfax County vote:
Centerville district; Centerville pie
cinct—Repeal, 46, against. 14; State
control, 41, State prohibition. 17. Clif
ton—Repeal. 82, against. 17; State con
trol. 81. State prohibition, 18. Pender—
Repeal. 15. against, 11; State control.
19. State prohibition. 7. Swetnam—Re
peal. 14. rgainst. 13; Stale control. 15,
State prohibition. 11. Wells—Repeal.
3. against, 0; State control, *8, State
prohibition. 0.
Dranesville district: Dranesville—Re
peal. 16. against. 16; State control, 21,
State prohibition, 11. Forestvlllc—Re
peal. 29. against. 34; State control, 32,
State prohibition, 32. Herndon—Re
peal, 135. against, 47; State control. 134,
State prohibition, 54. Pleasant Valley—
Repeal. 11, against. 5; State control, 13.
State prohibition, 5. Thompson's—Re
peal. 15, against, 29; State control. 26,
State prohibition, 17. Thornton's—Re
peal. 14. against, 4; State control, 15,
State prohibition. 3.
Falls Church district; Annandale—
Repeal. 60, against. 20; State control,
62. State prohibition, 18. Falls Church
—Repeal, 145. against. 75: State con
trol, 151. State prohibition. 69 West
End—Repeal. 50. against. 12: State con
trol. 53, State prohibition, 12.
Lee District: Bayliss—Repeal. 65;
against. 15; State control. 62; State
prohibition, 17. Burke—Repeal, 78;
against. 17; State control. 82; State
prohibition, 19. Woodyards—Repeal.
22; against, 6; State control, 22; State
prohibition, 6.
Mount Vernon District: Accotink—
Repeal. 52; against. 16; State control,
59; State prohibition, 8 Gum Spring
Repeal. 56; against. 10; State control,
55; State prohibition. 10. Moores—Re
peal. 53; against. 13; State control, 54;
State prohibition, 11. Pulmans—Re
peal. 52; against, 2; State control, 49;
State prohibition. 0.
Providence District: Fairfax—Repeal.
152; against. 57; State control. 153;
State prohibition. 54. Langley—Repeal,
170; against, 56; State control. 177:
State prohibition. 50. The Lick—Re
peal. 67; against, 17: State control. 68;
State prohibition. 16. Vienna—Repeal,
117; against. 95; State control; 118;
State prohibition. 96.
Totals—Repeal. 1.519: against. 601;
State control, 1,565; State prohibition,
572.
LOUDOUN BALLOT LIGHT.
County Registers 1,27* to 671 for Repeal
In 28 Precincts.
Special Dispaich to The Star.
LEESBURG, Va., October 4.—Al
though the vote cast in Loudoun yes
terday was light the county went 2 to 1
for repeal of the eighteenth amend
ment and for a plan of liquor control.
The vote in all 28 precincts was 1,271
for repeal, 671 against: 1.176 for a plan
of liquor control and 609 for continua
tion of State prohibition.
Six precincts voted against repeal.
These were: Hamilton, 38 for and 65
against: Bollington, 11—12; Silcott
Springs. 17—18; Irene, 26—28: Lincoln,
7—71. and Waters, 7—25. Other pre
cincts voted as follows: Leesburg, for re
peal 322, against 88: Aldie. 54—10;
Ashbum. 43—13; Areola. 49—10; Hills
boro, 52—52; Lucketts. 31—25; Lovetts
ville. 68—30; Mountville. 14—13; Blue
mont. 44—14: Purcellville, 74—72; Le
nah. 39—20; Roundhill, 53—27; Middle
burg. 85—18; Sterling. 34—11; Waxpool,
24—6; Taylorstown. 17—12: Unison, 51—
23; Philomont. 22—8: Waterford, 25—
24; Hughesville, 7—5; Blakeley Grove,
16—2, and Mount Gilead, 12—6.</text>
      </result>
        <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1930-03-06/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=prohibition</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CATHOLIC LAYMAN DEFENDS
PROHIBITION FOR DRY FORCES
-1
(Continued From Writ Pact.)
prospered under 41 yean at prohibition,
the statement said.
"During this time,” It added. “It h*»
been clearly demonstrated that prohi
bition has brought lasting benefit to the
citlaens of our State, It has increased
the economic well-being of our people,
has Increased savings, has decreased
poverty, and has made North Dakota a
safe place to rear our children, where
the contaminating influence of strong
drlng ha* been greatly curbed.
••North Dakota, being almost wholly
an agricultural State, we feel the gen
eral depression In agriculture which Is
in nowise aggravated by prohibition,”
the statement continued, adding that
“notwithstanding this general depres
sion, the wealth of North Dakota has
Increased materially during the years of
national prohibition.”
Figures were presented to show that
North Dakota agricultural products had
increased from $206,364,000 in 1921 to
$339,353,260 in 1929.
Burtness said that the people of his
State felt that the "good brought by
prohibition should be continued." Blew
ett had said that the lack of a demand
for barley and rye had resulted in a
surplus of wheat after prohibition.
Surplus Due to Propaganda.
Representative La Ouardla, Republi
can, New York, asked Burtness whether
this was not true and Burtness replied
that the wheat surplus had largely de
veloped as a result of propaganda put
out by the Government to bring about
an increase in wheat acreage.
Burtness said a lot of' barley crop
was consumed by •’near-beer,” adding:
“Any one who says we had no wheat
surplus before prohibition does not
know the facts. We always had a
surplus."
Questioned by La Guardia If corn
sugar production had not been in
creased. Burtness said that “we must
admit the fact that a lot of corn sugar
Is being used for the Illicit distillation
of liquor.”
“My friends in lowa,” the North Da
kotan added, “are greatly interested in
having corn sugar used in jams and
jellies. It does, of course, go into il
licit liquor.”
“You don’t mean that the tremendous
Increase in corn sugar is due to in
creased consumption of jam in this
country, do you?” asked La Guardia.
Burtness replied he was willing to
face the fact of illicit use of com
products, but insisted there had been a
large increase In legitimate consumption
of this product.
The North Ddkotan disagreed with
La Ouardia’s statement that real beer,
if permitted, would increase incomes by
using up more grain from the farms.
The witness argued the money spent
for beer would take much of the grain
producers’ Income.
Holds Many Lives Saved.
Mr. Callahan was next to testify.
He asserted that prohibition had saved
more lives than America lost in the
World War. He presented in support
of his claim statistics from the Census
Bureau.
The witness also denied that prohi
bition was identified only with protest
antlsm. As secretary of the Association
of Catholics Favoring Prohibition, he
said he could state that this was un
true.
Taking the average losses of life be
fore and after prohibition from alcohol,
cirrhosis of the liver and Bright's dis
ease and granting that 60 per cent of
cases of the last were caused by drink
ing, he argued that 140,800 lives had
been saved by the dry laws.
Deaths from alcohol had been re
duced. he said, from 5.3 to 2.8 per
100,000 of populaation, deaths from
cirrhosis of the liver from 12.2 to 7.6
per 100,000 of population and deattfs
from Bright's disease from 106.2 to 81.6
per 100,000 of population.
He arrived at his final figures, he
said, by basing his calculations on a
total population of 100,000,000. The
estimate of 50 per cent of cases of
Bright’s disease being due to liquor, he
took from the Senate prohibition in
vestigation of several years ago.
Callahan then denied that prohibition
was identified only with Protestantism.
Once, he said, the charge was made, and
is still heard occasionally, that "pro
hibition was Protestantism and pur
posely planned to interfere with Cath
olic services by ultimately making it
impossible to offer up the sacraments
of the mass.”
He declared that “nothing could have
been further from the truth” and that
such a charge was clearly “an Instance
of using religious prejudice for material
purposes.”
Society Woman Testifies.
Miss Ruth G. K. Strawbridge, a so
ciety woman of Philadelphia, testified
that she had conducted a poll of the
social register and had found an over
whelming majority of the women in
favor of dry entertainments.
The witness, a familiar figure in the
society of America's third city, present
ed responses to a letter she had sent to
society matrons asking them to show
their sportsmanship and co-operate in
enforcement of prohibition by abiding
by the law.
“Instead of finding an overwhelming
majority in favor of the liquor-drinking
fad at private gatherings and enter
tainments,” Mrs. Strawbridge said, “I
found that most of these society women
regarded it as an unutterable nuisance
and their only anxiety was. %s to how
most effectually to free themselves and
their families of it.
"They were eager to support President
Hoover loyally in his appeal for general
law observance. A favorite theme in
their response was that of the expense
of the custom and the disgrace of
maintaining relations with bootleggers
in order to keep up with the reputed
style of the day.”
Mias Strawbridge said she represented
no organization. She took sharp issue
with W. W. Atterbury, president of the
Pennsylvania Railroad and a director
of the Association Against the Prohibi
tion Amendment.
Criticises Atterbury.
In speaking of Mr. Atterbury she
said:
“There is one prominent Philadel
phian who recently made a statement
before your committee which I would
criticize as utterly unsportsmanlike and
unworthy a leader of public opinion,”
she said. “I refer to the statement by
W. W. Atterbury, president of the Penn-’
sylvania Railroad. Mr. Atterbury is in
favor of private prohibition by the rail
roads, not of the drink traffic, but of
the use of Intoxicants, habitual or oth
erwise. by their employes.
“This private prohibition, he told your
committee, is enforced by thf sharp
penalty of loss of livelihood laid upon
those who break the private law of the
railroads. But for the ‘personal lib
erty’ of the employers and those with
whom they mingle socially, Mr. Atter-
bury is against public prohibition. He
forgets that these very people are fast
drivers of automobiles on the public
highways.”
Miss Strawbridge then asked why Mr.
Atterbury, as president of a railroad,
r was so solicitous for the public welfare
that he rigorously denied personal lib
erty to drink to his employes driving on
engines on protected tracks and then
arrogated that liberty for himself and
his social acquaintance* who drive au
tomobiles on unprotected highways.
“Burely,” she said, “prohibition ap
plied to engine drivers means today in
America prohibition applied to every
body.”
Refers to Mrs. McLean.
She opened her argument by reading
a letter she had addressed to "women
of the so-called better class or social
set" and those prominent in civic affairs
in and about Philadelphia to show theta
sportsmanship for law enforcement and
in support of prohibition.
The letter referred to the example
set by Mrs. Edward B. McLean of
Washington at an Easter breakfast, at
which no alcoholic beverages were
served.
r “I have every reason to believe.” the
THE EVEyiy# STAR, WASHINGTON, D. ~C. t THURSDAY, MA&amp;6Hr S; 1980.
letter in part aald. “that her courage
In making this innovation in Washing
ton society met with the hearty ap
proval of President Hoover and of all
others, like himself, who are toying to
Inculcate in our people at this time a
more lively sense of their individual ob
ligation!) as American citizens."
She explained that the letter was
drafted, after conferences with former
Chief Justice William H. Taft, and at
tributed her campaign to aid in making
dry social affairs popular to his in
fluence.
"Counting the responses,” she con
tinued, “I discovered that in what had
been thought to be one of tbe wettest
of all cities, social leaden in great
majority were in favor of abolishing
the custom of serving drinks to their
guests. In disapproval I received 247
replies, and in approval 1,337, from
a mailing of 2,300 letten.
Refuses to Divulge Names.
“From many States in the Union, and
especially from the large cities, I have
received almost continually requests for
a list of names of those who favored
the proposal embodied In my letter.
These requests have come from promi
nent newspapers and well known cor
respondents. To all I have been con
strained to reply that in order to keep
faith with those responding I had never
divulged their names or the contents
of their letten of favor or disfavor. As
this work goes on in city after city
everybody communicated with is as
sured of the aame good faith which has
been maintained with the writers of
responses from PhUadelphia and its
vicinity.
“Fortunately the women who com
pose American society today are for the
most part more keenly conscious of
their public responsibilities and social
influence. My replies have come from
scores of matrons who entertain exten
sively, as well as from Government of
ficials. One matron whose social af
fairs have always been marked with
the flowing cup gave her first dry
party after she received my letter. She
wrote me that it was a huge success.
"Dry entertainments are becoming
more and more fashionable. If parents
make a joke of prohibition, so will theta
children. American mothers feel that
they cannot loiter today in facing their
responsibility. They must go forward
with the courage of the convictions.
They feel that parents can do more
by education and example to support
the prohibition laws and the President's
efforts than even the law can do. They
know that the youth of today have
wonderful capabilities and that it is
up to their elders to live lives that will
guide these children aright.
“Burely we cannot let our faith foil
us in a time when there is so much
need for clear, straight thinking. There
seems to be a searching on the part of
some people for a new false freedom.
Bach American citlsen must search his
own heart on this matter.
Dollar Mark Is Answer.
“Why are foreign countries so anxious
to defeat American prohibition? Why
are they working so strenuously against
our prohibition laws? The dollar mark
is the answer. The wine growers of
European countries have put up a tre
mendous sum of money to fight prohi
bition in our States. They are being
aided and abetted in effect by the in
terested pleaders for personal liberty
of the type of Mr. Atterbury, who main
tains an iron rule of private prohibition
among his employes, and of the type of
Pierre 8. du Pont, who is privately a
prohibitionist in his own gun powder
plant and publicly an anti-prohibttlonist
for himself and his motor-driving
friends.
“Are w« to destroy the Ideals of our
country by teaching our children to seek
this new selfish freedom which is denied
to the working classes? .This question
may not be looked upodr lightly, nor
may we expect our children to pay for
our selfishness.
“After all, the great question of law
enforcement rests with the people, and
all law enforcement can begin most
effectively in the home. If liquor is
served on the tables of American homes,
and if we mock the prohibition laiw and
patronize bootleggers, how can we expect
our children to carry on as good citi
zens.”
Writer Gives Tsstltoeny.
C. P. Connolly of Bast Orange, N. J.,
another witness, aald some people in
sisted that prohibition was responsible
for “our present lawlessness." But, in
his opinion, there was no more lawless
ness, If as much, as in pre-prohibition
days. Discussing conditions he had
found while collecting material for
magazine articles, the witness said: “It
seems almost impossible to enforce the
prohibition law in some sections, par
ticularly in my part of the country.”
He blamed the men who organized
tbe Association Against the Prohibition
Amendment for inciting disrespect for
law and added that “the great metro
politan dallies have been dropping poi
son into the breakfast cups all over the
Atlantic seaboard in the form of ridi
cule of the law.”
The witness was called down by
Chairman Graham for suggesting that
the wet witnesses who argued that fur
ther attempts at enforcement would
bring rebellion would have been dealt
with harshly in war time.
Asking that the prohibition law be
made a test of the sovereignty of the
Government, to “break up.once and for
all American lawlessness.” Connolly
warned that if the eighteenth amend
ment were repealed, it would open the
way for repeal of "other unpopular
laws.”
Moving pictures were held by the wit
ness to be responsible equally with pro
hibition for demoralization of the
younger generation. He added that
European youth was now just as wild
as young Americans. He claimed, how
ever, that the movement toward prohi
bition was increasing all over the world.
Connolly read a long list of figures
designed to show that crime had mount
ed steadily in the years Just preceding
enactment of the prohibition law.</text>
      </result>
        <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045774/1922-11-16/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=prohibition</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>William It. Anderson, suptrintendent
of the Anti-Saloon I-.eamie of New York.
Issued an appeal yesterday to the "pastors
of New York Slate who are for
law." warning them that "a few more
jars" like the election of November
will bring a sweeping and dt-cisive victory
for the opponents of prohibition.
"The opponents of liquor and the advocates
of law and order in the nation
as a whole .got kicked on the shins last
yuesday," said Mr. Anderson, "hut in
New York they were kicked 111 the eye.
I There are plenty of good reason^, but
the bald fact stands out that a nullifieationist
was elected Governor of New
York on n beer platform. The specific
1 dry gains in New York of the last few
years may be wiped out, and this State
set back where it was before it was
lifted up and pushed forward by the
nationwide movement.
1 "The situation will be infinitelyflorae
I unless this jolt has wakened th^ moral
citizenship with sufficient force to put
it into fighting temper again. But a
few more jars like this will bring a real
wet victory. And this jar will come
soon unless the moral element gets busy
1 locally and thereby guarantees the per"
manence of prohibition enforcement
1 against the treachery or stupidity of
politicians, and the accidents of political
upheaval, which In the future bid
I fair to be frequent and violent."
DRYS DECLARE BITTER WAR..
Chicago, Nov. 15.?A more bitter and
I relentless wet and dry fight is on than
was waged when prohibition was
adopted, Dr. Clarence True Wilson of
Washington, secretary of the board of
temperance, prohibition and public
morals of the Methodist Episcopal
Church, declared to-day.
"Prohibition has been weakly led. betrayed
in the house of its friends, sidetracked
by those who ought to have
given it the main line and the fight that
we ought to have avoided is now 011 and
it will be more bitter and relentless
than was the fighting when prohibition
was won," Dr. Wilson declared.</text>
      </result>
        <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1918-01-23/ed-1/?sp=16&amp;q=prohibition</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Will a Majority of States Say to
a Majority of American Citizens:
"You Don't Want Prohibition, But We Shall Jam It Down
Tour Throats, Anyhow 1
This is the interesting situation concerning the Consti
tutional Amendment for prohibition.
In this country a majority of the STATES are in favor
of prohibition. But the majority of the CITIZENS are
against prohibition they have at least not declared in favor
The proposed Constitutional Amendment makes it pos
sible for the States that want prohibition and that are en
titled as individuals to have it to force their views, opinions
and desires upon other States that do not want prohibition.
Thinly populated agricultural States have tried prohi
bition and some think that they like it.
In those States the well-to-do are able to drink what
they like and usually drink whiskey more or less.
It is found convenient for various reasons to control the
body of the people in Prohibition States, making whiskey
expensive and hard to get and the light and relatively i
harmless stimulants entirely inaccessible.
If tire various States of the Union favoring prohibition
were content to have prohibition FOR THEMSELVES and
permit other States to live as the other States choose, there
would be no difficulty, and that would seem to be the Amer
ican, way.
But the extreme prohibition fanatic, like the Moham-,
imedan, proposes to hypose his opinions and' his religion
upon others. I
Congress votes for a Constitutional Amendment that!
would permit a minority of citizens, in a majority of States.')
to impose their will upon all the States of the Union, con-1
"rolling the majority of American citizens by a minority of j
s the population in States favoring prohibition.
If this goes through there will be trouble of various
lands.
There will be trouble with labor, which feels that it still
has rights, including the right to live as it chooses while it
-does not interfere with others.
There will be serious trouble in the line of drunkenness
and drugs. Doing away with light beer and light wine
among workers will greatly increase the use of whiskey
illicitly made and of drugs.
r
There will be trouble for .some of the gentlemen that
now possess a great deal more of the world's goods than they
need.
There will be trouble for the South, that seems inclined
to impose minority rule on the North.
As tViA 'NVsiir Vnrlr World verv hlnntlv points out in a
strong editorial, the Southern States say to the North:
"You don't want prohibition, but we are going to make
you swallow it." The North, presently, may say to the
South: "Very well, you may nave your way. uui remem-
I -.a rhinrre tViof trnn in thp Snnth rlOTl't Want: Wfl
UC1, bUCIO CUB UUUJII vux. jw
are going tovmake you swallow those things including cer
-nrmiofinna nt -rnnr np otd Tiroblem alone the line of
the Fifteenth Amendment to the Constitution of the united
States."
It should not be necessary to stir up tnis sectional
feeling.
Every State that wants prohibition can have it and
should have it.
Every city, every district desiring prohibition ought to
have it, and may have it through local option.
In his newspap'er, the Sacramento Bee, Charles K. Mc
Clatchy puts the matter fairly and sensibly before the Legis
lature of uauiorma:
If California, as a State, de
sires to ko to prohibition, let her
citizenry say so at the polls.
But, Constitutional Amendment
of the United States or no Con
stitutional Amendment of the
United States, the Lefrislature of
the State of California has no
right in equity nor in common
decency to put itself in the atti
tude of Bayinjr to the people of
New York, and of Massachusetts,
and of Illinois, and of Pennsylva
nia, and to the majority of the
voters of these United States:
"You don't want prohibition,
but California will join the ranks
of the militant crusaders for the
milk-white flag and will jam it
down your throats. We know we
represent a minority of the people
of the United States; but if we
represent a soodly majority of
the Legislatures of this nation,
alleged to be dedicated to human
liberty and individual rights, we
will make you majority eat pro
hibition crow whether you want It
or not"
The whole thintr is un-American.
It is unrighteous.
It is tyrannical.
It is at variance with the very
essence of the Declaration of In
dependence and the very spirit of
the Constitution of the United
States.
It is to be hoped that there will be. found thirteen States
in the Union with sufficient respect for the Constitution of
the United States, for the rights of States, for the rights of
workingmen, and for the rights of THE PEOPLE OF THE
UNITED STATES, to prevent the imposition of the will of
a minority upon States that do not choose to be ruled by
the will of prohibition extremists.</text>
      </result>
        <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1928-09-19/ed-1/?sp=27&amp;q=prohibition</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>COLLEGE HEADS
SPLIT ON DRY LAW
Wide Difference of Opinion
Exists, Association’s
Survey Shows.
While the heads of many of the large
colleges and universities are in favor
generally of the principle of prohibition,
there is a wide difference of opinion
among them regarding the success of
the law, according to communications
read from more than a dozen large
educational iastitutions at a luncheon
meeting under the auspices of the Inter
co'-'egiate Prohibition Association in the
Raleigh Hotel yesterday. Dr. James M.
Doran, prohibition commissioner: Mrs.
17 M Pollock, president of the District
or Columbia Woman's Christian Tem
perance Union, and other leaders in the
prohibition movement were guests.
Some of the university heads, who
gave their views in answer to a recent
questionnaire, had mart** a special re
quest that their identity be withheld.
Says Situation Worse.
The head of one reputedly large in
stitution in New England, who Lofton
S. Wesley, executive secretary of the
Intercollegiate Prohibition Association,
said did not want his name given, de
clared: “Prohibition has greatlv im
proved the conditions in industrial life
end the status of workingmen in our
great shops and factories." but. "it has
made the situation worse than before'
among the leaders of so-calied society
and in the American colleger.”
The head of a university in Michican.
whose name also the executive secre-
tary would not give out. declared. "Pro
hibition is still in the experimental
■tage."
F. W. Boatwright., president of the
University of Richmond, stated that
the faculty and students of that insti
tution have always “frowned on drink
ing.'’
Arlo Ayres Brown, president of the
university of Chattanooga, declared
prohibition had been a benefit.
A communication from Temple Uni
versity said prohibition had not changed
Wrings there.
Walter Dill Scott, president of North
western University, declared prohibition
had improved conditions.
Swarthmorr Never Bothered.
Raymond Walters, dean of SWarth
more College, declared that institution
had never been bothered with drink.
Daniel L. Marsh, president of Boston
University, speaking strongly in favor
of prohibition, said. “I can hardlv think
of any greater disservice to the rising
generation than to scrap prohibition in
the manner A1 Smith and his crowd
propose."
M. G. Brumbaugh of Juanita College
declared conditions are generally bette’'
throughout the country as a result of
prohibition.
E. A. Burnett, chancellor of the Uni
versity of Nebraska, declared. "Th«
present law. if well enforced, would be
satisfactory.”</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-war-pigeons/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026853/1901-12-11/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=pigeon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Pigeon=Post at
j|| By Adrlen De J;
IN France, during the siege of Paris,
at a time when the German
armies were surrounding the capital
and cutting off the Parisian
population from all communication
with the outside world, Monsieur
Rampont, the then Postmaster-General,
conceived the idea of intrusting
to pigeons the transmission of news,
thus giving the inhabitants a knowledge
of what was going on in the provinces.
In this way those members of
U'EGC-BRE.D
lOHjA tMJI ntfco*
lli^x a veter/sn carrier
bird
the Government who had remained
in Paris were put in touch with their
colleagues of the National Defense
who were at Tours. In order to attain
this subject a certain number of
pigeons were conveyed by balloon from
Paris to Tours, whence they were set
free, bearing messages photographically
reduced to microscopic dimensions
on very light collodion films. In
those days the despatch was rolled up
and inclosed in a quill attached to the
tail of the pigeon. By these means over
150,000 official and, at the lowest,
1,000,000 private messages entered
Paris.
The great French shipping company
known as the Compagnie Transatlantique
deserves the credit of making
the first attempts to establish what
may truly be styled the seapost.
On March 26,' 1898, the steamship
La Champagne took aboard, for the
first time, eighty pigeons. Three
batches of birds were set free at a
6hort distance from the seaboard, and
this in most stormy weather. The
older birds safely reached their cote,
while the younger ones, unable to withstand
a pelting rain-fall, dropped into
the sea ill sight of those aboard.
On the following day, and under
Ilk infavorable wenther conditions,
L; 'bampa&amp;ne, Laving covered 3G0
miles, rescued the crew of tlie doomed
Bothnia. Seven pigeons were sent
l
THIS STRIP OF BAMBOO, CONTAINING
THE MESSAGE, IS FASTENED BOUND
THE PIGEON'S LEG.
~t?ii
lorm, eacxi oeanug u simnm ui-a.janu.
They took their flight r.t noon, and it
was calculated that they should either
reach land or some ship's matt. One
of the birds dropped on the deck of the
Chatterton, in the Eay of Biscay; the
Chatterton cabled to Paris end to New
York the- loss of the Bothnia. A second
bird was picked up by a freight
steamer, which thereupon shaped its
course for the locality of the disaster
came across tho derelict, and towed it
into an Irish port. A week later a
third pigeon, wounded, end minus its
despatch, reached its cote. The four
others were never heard of again.
The pigeons employed by the Compagnie
Transatlautique are selected
with the most rigirous care. The head
must be big and round; the bill relatively
short and surmounted with a
fleshy, heart-shaped excrcscence; the
+&gt;10 hrooat rrmst
c,yco ouiuu www
bunch out; the legs be short; and the
wings must meet on a narrow and
powerful tail.
In addition to being endowed with
an extraordinary instinct for shaping
Its course, a good carrier pigeon must
possess great rapidity of flight and
tremendous staying power. The firstnamed
quality?the "homing instinct,'
which is innate?is not susceptible of
any improvement. The two others
ii'
I.
A DRAGOON SCOUT-HE CARR
PIGEON ME
may be secured by means of progressive
and regular training. A pigeon's
education begins when it is but three
or four months old. It is conveyed a
mile distant from its cote aud then set
Sea and in War.
assaud, of Paris. ||jj
free. The' experiment is renewed daily,
the distance on each occasion being
imperceptibly increased. The bird's
education cannot be considered complete,
however, until it has attained
the age of three years.
On land the pigeon is able to cover
long distances, such as those between
T?r?non nml RriiKHPls or New York and
Chicago. Its ratio of flight, under normal
atmospheric conditions, is never
less than 31.15850 miles an hour, and
never exceeds 49.85300 miles on a
long distance.
The pigeons ~.re brought aboard the
Transatlantique steamers in wicker
cages having a drinking trough. As
soon as the French coast is out of
sight passengers desirous of sending
a dispatch are notified to prepare It.
In pursuance of this object the passenger
is handed a small rectangular card
on which ho is to write as legibty as
possible what he wishes to communicate,
plus the name end address of the
receiver;tbe card is then handed to the
clerk Intrusted with the transmission
of the message. The clerk put3 the
different messages into a group,photographs
then on a plaque to which adheres
a film, reducing the writing in
the course of the operation to such a
degreo that it cannot be deciphered
except i^itli the aid of a magnifying
rrlnea Tho nr.mf is flPVPlnnPfl. thf&gt;
t"- Mr
film detached and carefully rolled, and
then placed in a small bamboo tube,
hermetically sealed, end weighing
hardly cue and one-ba!f grarnmo. To
this tube is attached a light kid band,
provided with an automatic button
such .as is sometimes used to fasten
gloves.
As scon-at "ie tubes are ready the
pigeons are taken out of the baskets
containing them. These birds are en-"
tremely delicate?the slightest crushing
injures them and renders them un
THIS PIGEON IS WBABINO THE CHINESE
WEISTLE WHICH PROTECTS IT
AGAINST THE ENEMY'S TBAINED
HAWKS.
flt to do what is expected of them. The
clerk attaches each tube to the leg of
a pigeon by buttoning the kid band
above described. A pigeon is able to
carry a weight of fifteen grammes
without its detracting from the-rapidity
of its flight.
The loosings take placc in the morning,
or, if the skies are too overcast,
at latest before 2 p. m. Immediately
upon being loosened the pigeons circ'c
a few times about the ship, after
which they head straight for France,
in the direction of liennes. On arrival
at the horns station the tubes are
taken off, the lilms extracted from
then, and the photographic dispatches
enlarged to their original size. The
proofs thus obtained are pasted on a
glazed card ornamented with a pretjy
allegorical' design.
It has often been asked what constitutes
the marvellous faculty of shaping
its course by the carrier pigeon.
Neither sea nor mountains nor forests
interfere with this faculty. The bird
steers its course as if guided by a conpass.
As t'.e pigeon flies at an altitude
of not more than 1G0 yards to 180
yards it is not aided by its vision, for
in that case, given the rotundity of
the world, it would have to soar to an
altitude of 707G yards. Now, according
to aeronauts who have experimented
in the natter, the bird at that
altitude quickly drops to a much lower
one. Are they then guided by magnteic
currents? Are they endowed
with a sixth sense? The matter remains
a mystery.
It is impossible for the pigeon carried
away by a steamship to note the
course followed by means of one of
his five senses, since, during his journey
by ruil from Rennes to Havre, as
well as during the ose by sea, he has
been altogether cut off from ine cuter
world. And yet the bird possesses so
accurate a knowledge of the road It
has traveled that it makes for its
cote without the slightest hesitancy
and at a very normal rapidity of flight I
The carrier pigeon was of necessity
IES ON HIS BACK A SUPPLY OF
SSENGERS.
to be made use of for national defense.
During a campaign the success of operations
depends at most times on the
rapidity with which the commanderin-chief
is informed of the enemy's j
movements. To this end use 1b made
of cavalry patrols and of the field telegraph
and telephone. But to Insure
the safe arrival of Information none
of these means is so reliable as the
carrier pigeon. Scouts are liable to
be made prisoners or killed, telegraph
or telephone wires may work faultily
or be destroyed. These mishaps are
avoided by the use of the carrier pigeon.
In wcr time the role of cavalry consists
more especially in seeing and in
reporting what it has seen. It Is often
an easy matter to see, but to report
oftentimes attended by difficulties.
Herein lies the value of the carrier
pigeon. Troops on the march are accompanied
by portable cotes. They
consist of huge wirs cages provided
with lateral shutters; the cage is transported
on a two-horse four-wheeled
wagon. When it is found expedient
to reconnoitre the position of the enemy
or surprise its movements a few
pigeons are taken cut oZ ths portable
cote and placed In a wicker cago la
_
I
I
1
TTO CF THE PIGEON-CAGE W
AE
shape like an infantry soldier's haver?
i" oi?A AW Vlft Al?
SUCK; llim CttgV IB Birtipptu vu iuc unu
of a dragoon. Dragoons are preferred
for this service, for they do not carry
any carbinc slung about them, so that
the cage Is more easily attached to
tteir back. The dragoons gallop off
in the direction ordered, and before
coming in touch with the enemy they
commit to a very tfcin sheet of paper
the result of their observations. The
.sheet is then inserted in a tube, and a
little while after" loosing the pigeon
the officer at headquarters is in a position
to read the dispatch.
In order to fight the carrier pigeons,
to stop then in their flight ana intercept
the Information borne by them,
the Cermans have trained hawks to
hunt down these winged messengers.
The undertaking was at first attended
with difficulties, for, independently of
the necessity of establishing on a large
scale a system of falconry, the same
dispatch might be intrusted to several
pigeons, and hence it wouid be sufficient
for a single one to escape from
the talons of the birds of prey to ren.der
useless'all efforts made to capture
the dispatch. Moreover, the pigeons
are protected from tho assault of the
I
A CASE FOB A CAP.BIEH-PIGEON.
h-.wk by means of a little Aeolian or
Chinese-whistle affixed to its tail. This
whistle sounds as the bird flies through
the air, and frightens away the timid
hawk.
In Germany much importance Is attached
to the r.se of carrier pigeons in
time of war, and in the German Army
greatest oare is devoted tj the
training of the birds, the officers and
men being given instruction in the art
of handling them. In France the
scouts ere provided with a pigeon
apiece, which they carry in a little Iron
case fastened to the walstbelt. The
holder has a hinged lid, which is
opened when the bird is to be released,
and the head piece can be unfastened
when the bird Is fed.
In France carrier pigeons are like
horses?liable to be requisitioned in
time cf war. Every year owners of
carrier pigeons ere compelled to state
at the Mayor's office the number of
birds they own; while foreigners are
no longer permitted to breed carrier
pigeons in the country.
There are at present in Paris some
700 owners of carrier pigeons, possessing
14,000 pigeons, 7500 of which are
subjected to a regular course of training.
The total number of carrier pigeons
in France is 600,000.
The pricD of a pigeon varies according
to its pedigree, age and degree of
training. Some few years ago, at a
sale in England, seventy pigeons
fetched $3449. One of the birds, a
cross between the Antwerp and Brus|
sels breed, brought $243</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84036162/1904-12-29/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=pigeon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Carrier Pigeon Brings Tidings
From Far-Away Alaska.
Ben Rowland of the firm of Row
land Lucier, proprietors of the
Hoffman bar, had his attention at
tracted by a white pigeon Tuesday
morning, which had fallen exhausted
in front of his place of business. The
bird made several attempts to fly,
but was unable to make any distauce,
and Mr. Rowland easily captured it.
Upon examination he discovered it to
be a carrier pigeon and about its leg
was tied with a silk cord over a piece
of buckskin a rubber nipple. Inside
the nipple, carefully rolled in an oiled
paper, was this message, written with
pen and ink on a paper:
"300 miles N. E. Dawson, Dec. 2,
1904. Bill, the old place, if note is
received O. K. come at once. Lots of
gold. Finder of this bird please noti
fy Wm. Raymond, address 2152 Mis
sion St., San Francisco, Calif. Signed:
Jim Orr."
The pigeon's leg was badly irritated
from the cord which the message was
tied on with, and the flesh had been
worn to the bone, showing that the
bird had traveled a long distance.
Mr. Rowland immediately wrote to
the party mentioned in the message,
and it is possible that a bit of history
will develop from the pigeon's visit
to Havre.
Mr. Howland had a crate built for
the bird, which has fully recovered
from the effects of its journey, and is
enjoying its new home at the HIoff
man bar.</text>
      </result>
       <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058396/1917-08-15/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Pigeon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>SINCE tho days of Pharoah the
carrier pigeon has played an
Important part in warfare. De
spito tho perfection of tho wired
W and wireless telegraph and telephone,
V wig-wagging and other means of
j transmitting messages from head
quarters to flcld commanders, nothing
has yet been invented, unless it is tho
aeroplane, that makes these means of
communication absolutely safo from
I prying eyes and ears. Therefore, now
j as heretofore, the crmics of the world
i rely upon tho carrier pigeon as tin
J j safest and surest means of communl
'A I cation whoro absolute secrecy is os
i sentlal.
I While other nations of tho world,
j especial. Gormany, Italy'and Prance.
I havo devoted years of careful study
i to the broedlng and training of horn
i 1 ing pigeons, It has only been reccnt
r ly that tho United States deemed it
necessary to look for theso winged

messengers to accompany our various
expeditionary forces to France. There
arc soveral cotes of theso swift and In
telligent birds now under Army juris
diction, and already many of theso
pigeons havo been transported across
seas. Tho best known of theso cotes
is at Lansdownc, Pa., where that well
known Philadelphia sportsman, An
thony J Drcxol Blddlc, now a Captain
In tho United States Marino Corps, is
devoting much tlmo to supervising
tho training of the birds.
Record Breakers In Flock.
In this coto are many birds that
hold records for speed and distance
flights. Charles Jones, presldont of
tho National Carrier Pigeon Associa
tion, has taken a keen Interest In tho
new army flock and turned over two
of his record breaking birds, "Undo
Sam" and "Botty. "Uncle Sam"
still holds the record for an over
sea flight of 500 miles, while "Betty's"
600-inllo straightaway flight never
has been equalled.
It is generally conceded that tho
safest way to conceal a message to be
borno by a carrier pigeon is to en
fold It in a little tube that is tuckod
beneath tho bird's wing. Sometimes
tho noto is tied to its leg, or about
Its neck, but the tubo is moro popu
lar. When a homing pigeon is re
leased for its home flight It generally
soars to a tremendous altitude in
order to get its bearings. When It
has established its sense of direction
it darts away in straight flight to Its
goal, or cote. As tho bird flies bo
swiftly and at such a great altitude
tho chances of Its being shot by an
enemy sharpshooter Is romoto In ths
extreme and for this reason tho
chances for Its bringing homo tho
messago with trhlch it was entrusted
aro excellent
Birds Used By Pershinp:.
Uncle Sam's birds will bo exten
sively used onco tho American "Sam-
A
mies" get Into action and no doubt
General Pershing and his staff al
ready havo had occasion to uso them.
In the American coto are birds that
are tho progeny of "Simny.JJm." one
of the most noted homing birds In the
world. Jim electrified the homing
fanciers of tho world a few years ago
by a flight from Rio dc Janoiro to
Jeannctte, Pa a distance of 4,200
miles. It was tho flrst time a bird
of its kind ever winged Us way from
a point south of tho Equator. Jim
was liberated at Rio on May S, 1913.
Twenty-four hours afterwards ht re
turned to tho point of liberation, cir
cled about the cote for an hour or so
land then headed due north. Whether
it was tho intenso heat, or tho great
distance, most of which was ovor
strange and unfamiliar surroundings
abounding In denso tropical foliage,
none knows, but in any event Sunny
Jim did not return to this Pennsyl
vania cote until twenty-four days after
his liberation in the tropics. Bu' tho
all important point is, ho arrived.
Whereas tho natural instinct of tho
carrier pigeon is to seek his cote the
moment ho is liberated at some dis
tant point, nevertheless tho armies
of tho worid aro not relying on in
stinct alone. Theso birds aro train
ed Just as diligently and assiduously
as any other part of the wonderful
units that aro being so masterfully
weldod Into a perfect war machine.
The training is only accomplished af
tor weeks and months of patient effort
and now that tho time has arrived
for our army to tako its placo in tho
foreign battio line, great faith Is ho
ling pinned to tho feathered tribe that
is being transported across tho seas.
Dates Back to Pliaroah.
The part tho homing pigeons played
in the affairs of the world as previous
ly stated, dates back to tho days when
Pharoah's navigators wero sailing to
Egypt and released these homing
birds to let those at homo know tho
dato of their expected return. In tho
seventh century, history tells us, the
Arabs maintained a regular pigeon
posu Tho burdens of tho Dutch dur
ing tho sicgo of Leyden, wore mate
rially lightened by tho swift, flying
pigeons which conveyed their mes
sages and kept the lines of communi
cation open and safe.
Tho real valuo of tho homing pig
eon In war was best demonstrated
during tho slego of Paris in the Franco-Prussian
war, Just forty-four, years
ago. In tho course of this slego seventy-four
balloons were sent aloft all
frolghtcd with homing pigeons which
wero destined for Tours and other
points. It is said that upwards of
800 pigeons wero sont from tho Prov
inces to Paris during the slego and
that tho momentous messages they
conveyed would make a library of
500 volumes. It was Just prior to tho
siege that Barreswill and Dragon per
fected a process of mlcrophotography
by which two to three thousand letters
could bo photographed on a film two
Inches long by an inch and a half
wide. By placing tho negative or
positives In a storeopticon and throw
ing them on a screen, tho messages
Could easily bo read. More than 40,
000 such messages wero sont whllo
tho slego lasted.
Pigeon Post For Berlin.
Immediately after signing tho
treaty of peace Bismarck, realizing
tho importanco of a plgoon post In
war times, issued orders for estab
lishing cotes of tho best birds obtain
able In Berlin. Theso were main-
talncd soleJy for the use of tho army
and Germany's army has been using
the homing pigeon to a considerable
extent ever sinco. By IS 74 thero we:o
official pigeon cotes established at Co
logne. Metz, Strassburg and Baden.
To stlmulato the interest in broed
lng homing pigeons tho Kalsor gave
annual prizes for the swiftest and
strongest birds and ten years after
tho war thero wero ITS private hom
ing pigeon societies In Germany own
ing a total of 62,24 0 birds, cxcluslvo
of thoso In the army cotes.
Germany's Interest in the homing
pigeon was a stimulus to that In other
countries. Italy followed tho ex
ample set by France and Germany
and her cotes ever since havo been
world renowned. Sho now has six
teen army lofts, all filled with tho
very highest type of birds that brood
ers can produce. Russia has five of
theso military lofts and this means
several thousand birds, to say nothing
of the new crop of young birds that
annually come on, for tho pigeon is
prolific as a breeder.
Spain Uas Fine Ixfts.
Spain has a magnificent collection
of homing pigeons and its official lofts
are among tho finest in the world. Its
eighteen lofts, all under military su
pervision, aro scattored through tho
kingdom with a trainod body of sol
diers to look after and train tho birds.
Portugal,. llko her neighbor, has gono
In scientifically for pigeon breeding
and uses them extonslvoly for army
and sccrot scrvlco purposes. Portu
gal has fourteon lofts; Sweden and
Denmark flvo each. Holland has no
But all said and dono France leadB
tho world In tho utilization of tho
carrlor pigeon. Thero aro upwards
of 100,000 birds in the hands of skilled
breeders and trainers throughout that
Republic, all of which aro subject to
bo commandeored by tho government
at an Instant's notice. As It Is France,
learning tho. value of theso winged
mossengers in the Franco-Prussian
war, now has twenty-eight military
pigeon lofts, most of them along tho
eastern boundary in tho vicinity of tho
battle front- There are 100 birds in
each of tnese lofts.
French scientists after a series of
exhaustlvo experiments have decided
that tho homing pigeon relics upon tho jH
sense of smell, rather than that of
sight, to find its way home. This do
clslon was reached after testing every
sense theso birds aro endowed with.
Tho senses of sight, hearing and smell
wero all deadened In turn. First tho
birds wero turned looso far from
home and blindfolded. They arrived
at their cote according to schedule.
Then their ears wore scaled with wax fM
and still they arrlvod. But when their
nostrils were closed with wax tho
birds becamo bewildered and helpless JM
and floundered around, soon refusing
to fly at all. Tho scientist's cxplana- IH
tlon is that each locality has its indl
vidual odor for tho homing pigeon,
and by circling aloft the pigeon final
ly gets into tho air current frolghted
with tho odor of tho pigeon's home lo
callty and by following this curront
ho arrives ultimately at his cote.
230 Miles In Five Hours. j IH
A flight of 250 miles in from flvo to
soven hours is regarded as an ordi-
nary feat for a pigeon. A fow can
make 500 or 600 miles In tho satao
time. Somo of tho best records over
attained wero hung up by American
birds. A bird namod Nym, owned jH
and bred by J. R. Husson of Cresson.
Pa., flew from Now York City to
Cresson, a distance of 243 miles, in JH
337 minutes. That was away back in
1SS0. The bird's avcrago speod wa3
at tho rato of a mllo in 5S V seconds.
In a flight from New York to Stouben- jH
vllle, Ohio, or a dlstanco of 375 miles,
San Francisco, owned by a Hobokon.
N. J., man maintained an avcrago of
fifty miles an hour. A record which
long stood was that from Montgomory,
Ala., to Fall River, Mass.. 1040 mllos,
made by Alabama, a noted bird. Tho
pigeon was in his loft ten days after
liberation.
</text>
      </result>
       <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86091188/1919-06-20/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=pigeon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>GREAT WAR WORK OF PIGEONS
ON BATTLEFIELDS AND THE SEA
Carriers of Vital Messages Ever
Since Battle of Marne
in 1914.
U-BOAT IS TRAFPIO BY BIRO
New* From Trench** Taken at Fu
Speed to Headquarter* and Supply
tin**—Information Gained
From Captured Pigeon*.
Purl« At ih<* Trrnin gala of I'nrl*
fimy In* «'in n memorial, tl»« work of
1 lu rtli.till, on which I* ln «er I Ix-d
"Mutuumnt to Ho- ItulliMinlst* nnd Car
rier l*lg«-<>n* of Ix7o Whitt meiiiorlal
will acknowledge tin* services of car
rier pigeon* in t|„. world «nr of lot
ÏÎMH remains tu tu* »een, hut their work
ainlil Imrruge lire, bursting shrapili'l,
the zip zip of machine gun hüllet» »nil J
the death destroying game* vt.i» of
enormous value.
Carrier pigeons were ttieil on nil the
hattlefr.xits hut their lient work wu*
on the western front, from the chan
nel t" the SwIm border nml from the
Alp* to tin* Atlrlatlr gulf. They oar
rhil messages »t the Munie, when the
Hun- were driven hark hy Marshal
Jiiffre. Iliindreil» Were u»eil In Ihe
tail tip of the Yuer, In Klan der», when
the Belgian* and the Kreneh halted
the Herman advance und they nmdn
many and frequent trip* In the flrat
tintlle of Yprea, In Ihe drive on Ihe
channel port* when the ftrltlMh. Kreneh
nnd Belgian* Ntoppiil the (lertttana do
d»h, y In the tlfinl tmttle nt the clone
«>f IIM4. They aided In the capture of
Neuve Chapelle hy the British and
they died In number* with the British
Tommie» at the second hattle of Ypren,
when the German* advanced toward
the Ywr canal using for the first time
poisonous gn*. Again the bird* did
valiant aervlce when the Kreneh tried
to break through In the Chuinpagne In
the full of MM3, and In the whole
aerie* of the Verdun nttai-k» lasting
through July, oftentlmc* the only (Him.
mtinleNtlon* with men In advanced *ta
hm» were the dog» that crept through
the barrage* nml the carrier pigeon*
that relumed with ineHNage*. Where
w
telephone and wlrel.-*» broke down,
nnd mi ii could not survive the storm
of shell fire. It Is .......riled that 07 per
rent of the message* carried by carrier
pigeon* came safely through.
Told of German Retreat.
When the Herman* ret Ir.» I to the
"Hindcnburg line," It w a* carrier pig I
et. n* carried forward Into the front
ndvanee lines that brought hark the
liews of the retirement long before
telephonic communlcittlnn could he c*
tnbll-hnl. Through the whole area.
"ipiui e mile*, on a ft ont of list
tulle* from Arras to SoUsous, carrier
pigeon* did th.-lr work effectively And
wherever the American* fought, at
('anttguy. Chateau Thierry, Torcjr,
lloiiresrtie*. It.dleau wisst, Onde-en
l»He. Huzuni y. Jiiulgonne, IVreenTur
•Icnols, mimic, t'lcrges, liter* Ai'cron,
I Isme*. I'rapelle, Itazoche*. Juvigny,
St. MlliM. Argonne f.ir.-st carrier
pigeon* were likewise on the Job.
A earlier plgi»&gt;n aided In capturing
a 1' bout and h&gt; r crew A const watch
er on one of the loneliest part* of the
west coast at sundown saw the tip of
a periscope arise and then the conning
lower of a K boat. The underwater
Lout stopped, and the »Hirers and crew
were seen on deck Ihe lookout titan
tied it note hearing the Information to
the leg of a carrier pigeon urn! released
It fr»iti Id* basket The next morning
a Herman submarine, which had run
out of gasoline, ami It* otllcers and
crew were taken to a naval *ub ha*e.
A llrlllsh patrol t»&gt;at was itlacuv
eiisl hy a Herman submarine nml tor
cdis'd nnd shelled. The skipper, hnv
lug on board a carrier pigeon, wrote a
brief message, telling Ills |*&gt;-»ltlon nnd
what bad huptwited As the boat
punk, the *kt|q&gt;cr began swimming for
some wreckage to Hing to The p'gcoit
went up gradually In a spiral, and the
Hermans, seeing It. began «tesuing at
the hirst. The skipper drifting on the
wreckage, gave up hope when he saw
the bird had been tilt Twenty mite*
away, however, tt lighted on n patrol
png destroyer. Its »liver gray plunmg«


RACHEL M MILLAN BABY CAMP IN ENGLAND
of fouturv* at this t&gt;lg KiiglUh nursery camp I« outsit »I.
ri-.-ping quarter* for the children. Every day that wonth.i
Clt-idrv-u u.kv Otis healthy wag «C getting their afterooou uup
penult* the
nwu r _
»peeked with blood. It* tall feather*
ahot away, and one of it* wing» wound
ed. The commanding of!ii*er read the
iin-»»age. the deatroyer wn* ru*hed at
full »Jieed to the plaee Indien led. and
within three-quarter* of an hour from
the time that the pigeon wn* -eut off
the officer* and crew of the patrol Were
picked up where liny clung to the
w recknge.
Spy With Pigeon*.
Alt American at Liege, In writing of
the lier man advance, told this Inci
dent
"A* I returned to the elty, walking
along ihe Hiver Mcu»o, I *»w one who,
ohllvloii* of war and It* alarm», wit*
dangling hi* leg* over the water nnd
peacefully dulling. The battle In the
air, which lie must have witnessed,
had nut moved him. The certainty that
the Herman* were only a few mile*
ier tied him. lie
tanked Id* pip*- and placidly cant hi*
Ilm*. It wn* aoothlng to overstrained
nerve* to *ee that chap, hut It wn*
only a few hour* later that 1 learned a
Oilman *py hud been arrented a* he
poled a* a fl»heriiinn, with a creel full
of carrier pigeon»."
Another »tory rend»:
"In lln* cowl, habit and tonsure that
mark the monk a young man told hl»
head* aboard lln- train hound for Ant
werp. And a woman, hardly more
than a girl, kept her eye* fastened on
the man of prayer*. She atuilled on
the devotion with which hi* linger*
»lipped from dorade to decade of the
long, well worn rosary that hung from
Ihe cincture about Id* waist. Hut, al
though Id* lip* appeared to move In
humble supplication, the woman »aw
that he had failed to kls* the crus*.
The lapse was significant.
"'Spy!' the girl hl»*ed Into the face
of the alleged Hnoeltc. In an I lint a lit
two giiurd* had seized the man nnd
rti»hed him down the train corridor.
The woman examined the »mull wicker
hn*ket behind In the »eat. Lifting the
lid, »he found three pigeons."
Get German Pigeon*.
A new* dispatch briefly Muminarlzed
such a find thus:
"A Herman trawler was captured hy
n ItrltUh warship near the Orkney
Islands to the north of Scotland. She
Is believed to have been engaged In
*l'&gt; l,, furrier pigeon» were found
0,1 ,,0 n
In ference ha* already been mad
Ihe number of message* carried hack
to the French lines hy carrier pigeons
In the defense of Verdun. A pigeon
Currier pigeon* t II headquarter* of
the progress of a battle. Here 1*
typical icporl when the trench arm)
fought along the Aisne:
"It Immediately apls-ared that th*'
destruction of the Herman defense
had I..... n accomplished with as much
slice, s, as could he hoped for In so
dltttcult a country. Hy 7:!«) a-
learned hy carrier pigeon and other
means that tin- Chuleau the French left near Alternant had
I,cell carried, and that at the center
Miilmulsoii Fort was taken. At H:t.
Allemant village had been occupied,
the prisoners numbered a thousand
and the Frein-h assault troops were ad
vnnelng aero*.* the central plateau to
ward Vuudesson and Mont Humasse
quarry. At lodti» the new* was that
they were at the north of HUI 17H, the
fun her spur of Mulnutison plateau
and In n quarry 22*) yards west of H*e
fort. Hy 2 l- r P. nt. tin* villages of
Chnvlgnon and Vuudesson, with sev
eral neighboring quarries lying on the
norlhern edge of the Aisne hills, had
I....... occupied. <'havlgnon was the
furthest point contemplated In tin
plan and represented an advance of
one and one-half miles made In the
face of the best remaining troops of
the Herman empire."
Aided by Camouflage.
While many carrier pigeons changed
their habits of spiraling. Unding It a
dangerous practice and learned to lly
hack and then forward at an altitude
comparatively low, camouflage aided
birds considerably In getting buck to
their loft carrying with them messages
from troops In front. At Fort Vaux,
In the hattle of Verdun, the crown
prince's army had u special group of
men shooting down carrier pigeons as
they left the fort.
And another story of Verdun. It
win» (U Tblttumont, slsteCO
taken, lost ami retaken. Wireless and
telephones hud long ceased to exist.
No human being could cross the ter
rain. The commandant was lu des
perate need of communicating with
the rear. Suddenly the glasses re
vealed a dog, crouching on Its belly,
crawling through the flashes, and in
a moment of temporary lull leaping
forward. On Its hack was a pannier.
Nearer und nearer the dog came, nnd
prayers were Involuntarily offered as
the beast flattened out here and .here
In the debris for shelter. Another lull
and the dog leaped forward and nt
Inst It scampered Into Thtnumont with
the pigeons safe In the pannier. On
the (log's collar was this message:
"We relieve you hy attack on Froid
terre, 8 tn."
"Stoii the Herman battery on mu
left. Here ure the elements for |»>int
lug,' was the written message of the
commandant sent back hy one of fhf
pigeons. Another momentary lull nn(
the pigeon Is released. I tog and pig
eon, faithful and distinguished friend.*
of limn, have done their work U&gt; save
clvlllziitieu.</text>
      </result>
       <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86091096/1921-02-25/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Pigeon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TIME NEEDED 10
MANAGEPIGEONS
Good Blood First Requisite of
Homing Bird That Wins
Blue Ribbons.
PATIENCE QUITE NECESSARY
Distance From Home That Bird Is
Taken Must Be Increased Very
Gradually—Racing Is One of
Most Fascinating Sports.
To Noah must be given the honor
of owning the first homing pigeon of
which there Is written record. Al
though the olive tree from which
Noah's dove or pigeon brought a sprig
to him doubtless looked fair to the
bird after t'ie weeks of close confine
ment on the ark, yet that marvelous
Instinct for Its home, which Is one of
the chief characteristics of the homing
pigeon, brought It back once more to
the bout afloat on the face of the wa
ters. The Egyptians, Greeks and
Romans all used the messenger
pigeon In their days of power, and to
Starting the Bird on Its Homeward
Journey.
day pigeon breeding, rearing, and rac
ing forms a pleasant and Interesting
recreation for many people in prac
tically all civilized countries of the
world.
Gallant War Services.
During the recent war, notwith
standing the use of telephones, wire
less und all the methods of communi
cation which modem genius has in
vented, pigeons played an Invaluable
and gallant part.
In the United States there is prob
ably not a city which cannot boast of
racing-pigeon fanciers, while clubs and
associations for the advancement and
enjoyment of the facinatlng spoYt of
racing the birds are being constantly
formed in Eastern, Western, and to
some extent in Southern cities. Lofts
of homing pigeons are maintained by
the United States Department of Agri
culture at the government poultry
farm at Beltsvlile, Md., and the de
partment holds a membership In the
Washington Racing Pigeon club, a
branch of the American Racing Pigeon
union. Many of the Washington club
races flown during the past summer
and fall have been won by Department
of Agriculture birds, which number
about 250.
Just what faculty enables the hom
ing pigeon to return to its loft many
miles nwa.v Is a point of dispute
among eminent homing-pigeon breed
ers. Some attribute It to remarkable
instinct. Others maintain that this
bird has sight so brilliant and power
ful that It Is able to see much farther
than any other species, while there are
some who claim that it is the ex
treme and strong attachment for
home, coupled with a peculiar memory.
Training the Birds.
It is necessary to keep the birds in
good condition with plenty of outdoor
exercise, both In good and had weath
er, If they are to have endurance for
long flights. The young birds are
usually hatched In February and
March. During the time when the eggs
are being incubated and the young
cared for, only one of a pair is trained
each day. On alternate days the other
is shipped to the training station. In
this way the breeding is not interfered
with, and the eggs or young are never
left without one or the other of the
old birds.
In the beginning of the training the
birds are conveyed In a basket not
more than six or eight blocks from
their lofts to an open spot away from
buildings. The basket Is faced toward
the loft and the birds liberated at
once. At this distance pigeon spe
cialists advise practicing them from
all points of the compass. The next
step Is to select the route over which
It Is Intended to fly the birds. From
half a mile the distance can be in
creased to 1 mile, then 5, 10, 50, 100,
and 300, until the longest distance has
been reached.
Fly in Clear Weather.
Clear weather should always be se
lected for the birds' flights, for many
birds are lost during a stormy period.
Then, too, good weather is especially
necessary for rapid flying.
It Is considered best not to be in
too great haste in having the birds fly
a long distance. The young birds need
the time to develop their faculties,
strengthen the muscles, educate the
sight, and cultivate the memory and
Intelligence.</text>
      </result>
       <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84022835/1919-01-16/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=pigeon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TMIK records of tills war tiro replete
with stories of thi couitiKi'iMis work
performed by carrier pigeons while
saving the lives of our soldier, but
no Incident bettor Illustrates wtmt
thev haw nicomidMicd than their
uetlxitlos In tlit battle of Helium
court ami Dead Man's" hill. An en
tin' French regiment was cut otT from
comrades, completely cirniuinleil for four
lia.v.s. anil with no method of communicating word
of Iholr plight to the policial In enuinmnd. That
fourth night one of the men scouting In N Man's
Land stumbled over n dead comrade on whose
hark was strapped a hasket cnu.xlng two little
pigeons that dining the fiiur-dn hnttle had been
safeguarded by the bnd of their caielaker. Ten
derly the scout brought the basket and bliiN
back to the colonel on the hill. Lnrly the net
morning messages weie written. allled to the
legs of the birds, which. ebaiistid und dust
soiled, but Imbued with hidoiultiihle spirit and
pluck, weie liberated wafted Into the air by the
pr.iyers and wishes of the ie;:liuent, bearing with
them the only lemuliilug hope for these thousands
of men and the happiness of other thousands In
their families at home. Shortly afterward both
birds Muttered wearily Into their loft hack at
headipia.iters: and In a soitle ordered by the cen
tra I the enemy was drlen back and the icglmciit
saved.
One of the olilcers of that regiment Is now In
Washington, and lie has promised himself tint
now the wnr Is oxer he will have a loft of the
best birds he can gel. and the best care and at
tention that Is possible will be but a slight pari
.of his iucnMiro of appiedation and gratitude to
the little feathered messenger.., to xvhom he and
bis comnides owe theli s.
These little birds h:i. been used In almost
every conceivable wa.x to get xxord back to the
leserves or to headquarters xvhen all other
means of communication failed.
I'ari'ier pigeons are not only used by the In
fantry and the navy, but are used fieiptently by
the air urn lee. At the Dunkirk hydroplane sta
tion they have an enviable record. There has not
been a single accident to a plane, nor the loss of
a plane In combat, where word of the occurrence.
xviih not brought hack by the pigeons which are
a part of the equipment of the planes. Instances
of the value of the messengers could be multi
plied without number, but It Is more Interesting
to recount how these birds are bred, reared and
housed under xvar conditions.
The pigeon's ability to do all of these xvonderful
tasks lies In Its faculty of orientation, that is, Its
power to know as soon as It Is released In what
direction Its homo loft Is and to fly directly to It.
The perfection to which orientation is developed
In the highly bred and trained homer was recently
demonstrated at a pigeon fly conducted by the
pigeon section of the signal corps, when 8,100
homing pigeons were released In Washington for
a My to New York city, '2'2 miles. To a single
Mid, these pigeons ran out of their coops and
arose In tho air with the speed of an express
train, and after taking a half circle to get their
bearing were ofT for Ncxv York. Every one of
tho pigeons xvas reported to have arrived prompt
ly nncl the llrst arrival tnado the trip In fi hours
und -10 minutes. Surely It did not btop to read
many sign posts on the xvuy.
Just how the homing pigeon developed this
poxver of orientation Is u moot question, hut It Is
certain that It has been cultivated through cen
turies uutll uow It Is almost uncanny. What
guides the pigeon back to tho loft xvhere It first
"took to the nlr" Is a quality called by many
names, and you will flud that each person knows
that ho has the answer to the riddle. Some call
It lnnato love of home; others uttrlbutu It to fac
ulty, atmospheric conditions, sight, or memory.
Personally, 1 cannot call It anything moro or less
than instinct, highly developed. Wo And it In
lesser degree In horses, dogs mid cuts, and In
other blrda It seems to bo developed n llttlo less
nmrkodly, but with sufllclent nccuracy so thnt
they migrate nunually thousands of mllen without
tho nid of any other compass than their Instinct.
When wo remember tho potent power of selec
tion and think of the years and generations of
careful breeding und selection which tho homing
pigeon has undergone It is not to xvonderful thut
they have developed the homing Instinct to u high
degree. I have seen their cousins, the fan-tailed
pigeons, bred to such n degriMj of fineness that
they weighed only a fexv ounces apleco and were
AJLVi. rfip&amp;?f ryTo'PAcA'a'JAWf?
ill frr V4-. w
MrCff(jV.?J?JJAcr'7?GV TfSfXCrtr
so nervous that the.x could not stand still they
were like the lialr-spilng of a xxateh. constantly
preening and din-Mug an 1 on the mow. In very
early times homing pigec us weie In xogite In
Kgypt, fireeee and among the Udimmd-. Haclng
pigeons has been n royal and national sport In
llelgliini, France, ltal. Turkey. Kgypt and K'ig
land for hundreds of years. It xxas Introduced
Into this country In the ieventlus and has enjoyed
a fair and steady growth until now there are
three nntlonal homing pigeon associations with n
membership of more than 'J.000 breeders.
Much time Is spent In teaching the pigeon all of
the trlekw which count when tho bird Is actually
racing In competition svlth other pigeons. It is
taught to enter I be loft Immediately upon Its re
turn, for u bird 'hat does not enter so that tho
message It carries can be taken from It Is of very
little value as a messenger. Nothing Is moro
exasperating to the fancier or racer than to have
the pigeon return and cool Its anatomy and vloxv
the scenery for a half hour before entering the
loft. It Is nearly suf'iclent cause to make the
trainer of pigeons lose his faith In pigeon nature j
besides It gives the neighbors a chance to make
remarks about the fullgrown men playing with
birdies. Once the bird is Inside the loft It can
not emerge, since each loft Is equipped xxlth n
trap through which the bird can enter at any tlmo
but cannot go out unless the trap Is set for exit.
The ordinary bain variety of pigeon or those
bred for the production of squabs for market and
the racing homing pigeon should not be con
fused. They are as dKtlnct and have as many
points of difference as hiwo the big draft horse
and the high-strung, nervous racing horse. The
ordinary pigeon has xery little homing ability,
whereas the homing plgaon Is kept and bred ex
clusively for that faculty. They are also bred for
speed, and every muscle which Is used In Might
Is developed almost at tho expense of the other
muscles of Its body. In races the actual speed
recorded Is almost beyond belief. .Speeds of 1.8.ri0
to 1,'.)00 yards per minute, or DO miles per hour,
hnvo been madu for short distances, and It Is not
extraordinary (or a bird to cover In excess of oOO
miles In n single day. The record for 1,000 miles
Is 1 day, 11 hours. LM minutes and 11 seconds, und
xvas made by a bird named Ilullet, and the longest
successful race was 1.0S0 miles from Denver,
Colo., to Springfield, Mass. (tlmo I'l days, 3 hours,
1!2 minutes), although Instances aro recorded
xvhere birds sent from Noxv York to the I'uclMc
const as breeders, have, on liberation or escape,
returned from California, ox-or the mountains and
plains to their old homes In New York.
At various times In this country tho army and
navy have decided to use use carrier pigeons in
their work, but with lndl fferent success until tho
recent xvur. The old reports aro rather amusing
xvhen considered In tho light of present-day knowl
edge of what can ho done with tho birds when
handled properly. Pigeons were used In tho navy
more than 20 years ngo, but failed through lack
of proper care. At the tlmo of the Mexican bor
der trouble pigeons xvero again tried, but with
llttlo success for the saino reason and through
lack of time for acclimatization.
Homing pigeons were first put on a business
llko basis In the army In Mnrch, 1017, In tho
enstern department. In Nox-emher of that year
tho pigeon section of the land division of tho sig
nal corps was organized, and slnco then rapid
progress has been mado in this country and
abroad. Hundreds of
lofts have been built and
equipped In this country,
and In the early days
Uiiui.x pigeons xvero frldP
pul oxei-seas. Men have
been selected and trained
In the science of pigeon
'ireedln;:. rearing and Hy
ing. Many of these huvo
already found service
overseas In the care of
lofts and the birds of our
armies. It has been nec
essary to train a Inrtfo
number of people in this
worlc. as it was practi
cally new to each person
xvlni look It up. The
training of olilcers und
men In the use and care
of th'; birds at the front
and lb the forwarding of
messages all took tlmo.
Unfortunately the plR
cons could only My "Vi
could not tnlk, necessitat
ing Mio xvrltlng of the
messages. Some xvag 1ms
proposed to Improve the
pigeon by crossing It
xxlth a parrot, thus ellra-
of xvrltlng the messages.
might have something to
Minting the necessity
However, the pigeon
say about the matter.
One of the most dllllcult parts of tho work of
Introducing pigeons Into the army service was to
Instill Into the minds of tho olilcers mid men the
fact that the pigeons are reliable. That they aro
reliable Is proved by the experience oversews,
xvhere the birds nre retained in forward positions
xvhlle any other method, whether telephone, tele
graph, Induction buzzers, wireless, wlgxvag or run
ner Is nvnllable, and only xvhen everything else
falls, and only the birds remain, then through
barrage, gas, and every other of the diabolical
Inventions of xvar, mrrs ti.nn 07 per cent of tho
messages Intrusted to our pigeons are safely and
speedily delivered by them to headquarters.
These messengers nre carried to tho front In
especially constructed wicker baskets which can
be carried handily by the soldier Intrusted xxlth
their care. Hack of tho lines the pigeons are kept
In either of txvo kinds of lofts or home, station
ary or movable, but tho essentia! feature of each
Is the same. Kvery effort Is made to meke eoch
bird tfomfortnble, happy and attached to Its home.
This 1h done most effectively by the method of
feeding, ns tho uppionch to the bird's affection
Is through Its stomach, the same ns with genus
homo. Each loft Is equipped with n trap through
which the birds ore taught to enter and leax-e
xvlthout fear. Each time the bird enters the trap
nn alarm is automatically rung, notifying the
attendant of tho return of tho bird, that the mes
sage may be Immediately obtained and forwarded
to headquarters.
Ilefore the late xvar If you bad told n pigeon
fancier that you could move his pigeon loft as far
as s"0 miles and thnt tho pigeons xvould return to It
swiftly and accurately he would probably have
laughed at you and snld something about your
being u novice In the pigeon racing and breeding
game. The movable loft Is one of tho ndvances
In pigeon lore that the xvar has brought out.
This Is a very Important development, ns It Is
highly desirable that tho lofts always be near to
military headquarters and available for instant
removal with headquarters as conditions may re
quire. These movablo lofts are very xvell con
structed and nro Interesting homes for theso Itin
erant messengers. They ure outfitted with nesting
boxes, observation traps, storage space for feed,
water, and accommodations for one or two at
tendants xvho nre constantly on duty. In fact,
they remind ono of tho circus wagons that travel
with the smnllej; circuses about tho country.
Another Innovation developed xvas the "oxvl ex
press." There were pigeons nt tho front thnt
developed tho fnculty for seeing nt night
nnd theso xvero called veritable human night owls.
In fact, they eumo home much moro steadily nnd
accurately than some of their clvlllnn brethren,
xvho xvero wont to bo habitual riders of tho "oxvl
express."
Tho sport of racing nnd breeding pigeons Is duo
to receive nn Impetus as a civilian sport noxv thnt
tho xvar Is ended, nnd tho progress made under
xvar conditions should not bo nlloxved to lapse.
Thousands, of soldiers xvlll hnvo become familiar
with the birds and xvlll hnvo a warm regard for
them. There xvlll bo many xvho xvlll Bhuro tho
feeling of the oMlcer xvho xvns mentioned In tho
Hint part of this nrtlclo ns having been saved by
the pigeons In the hattlo of Dcthuncourt und
Dead Man's hill.</text>
      </result>
           <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1915-02-07/ed-1/?sp=40&amp;q=pigeon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>FREQl
newa tilfn.
REQl'ENT references In the war
v to tho use of homing
pigeons discloses tho Interesting
fact tlul these winged messen
gers have proved themselves so useful
and so trustworthy that they cannot be
supplanted even by such up to tho min
ute devices for conveying Information
ns the Held telephone, the wireless tele
graph, the heliograph, the motorcycle
and the aeroplane, all of which are
freely used by all tho forces In the Held,
Indeed, notwithstanding the wonderful
progress that has been made In modes
of conveying Intelligence the homing
Pigeon will be more extensively used In
the present conflict than In any other
recorded In history. At least prepara
tions have been going on for years to
this end, For the first time pigeons
drilled as carefully and as persistently
ns any other part oi ,hc military estab
llshment will be tried in war-
England.
right Mrs. Harcourt, Lady Ran
From thu earliest times recorded in
history the homing pigeon's wonderful
faculty of getting home In a hurry has
been utilized In conveying messages, In
the days of the Pharoahs navigators
sailing to Egypt used to release pigeons
with messages to let tho folks know
they wero coming home. In tho seventh
century thu Arabs maintained a regular
pigeon post. Pigeons also rendered val
liable -services to tho Dutch at the slego
of Leyden In 1571.
But It took the slego of Paris during
the Franco-Prussian war forty-four
years ago to establish fully tho valuo ol
tho homing pigeon ns a messenger.
During the slego seventy-four balloons
ascended carrying pigeons to Tours and
other points. It was estimated that 800
pigeons were sent from tho provinces
to Paris during thu siege, nnd that tho
total number of messages carried by
these winged messengers would make a
library of 600 volumes. Barreswill nnd
Dagron developed a process of micro
photography by which 2.000 to 3,000
letters could be photographed on a film
two niches long nnd nn Inch and a half
wide. Tho messages were read by plac
ing them In a stereoptlcon and throwing
them on a screen. Upward of 40,000
Hii'ii messages were sent during tho
siege.
So entirely successful was the pigeon
post that one of the first things' Bis
marck did nftcr the treaty of peaco
was signed was to establish n pigeon
loft la Berlin fur the use of the army.
g Pigeons Useful
9-P
European Armies Have Developed
Birds as Bearers of Despatches
to a Remarkable Degree
By 1874 there wero military pigeon lofU
at Cologne, MeU, Strassburg and
Baden. Thu Emperor gave prizes to
eticourago the sport of pigeon racing.
Ten years' after the war thero wero
no fewer than 178 private homing
pigeon societies In Germany owning a
total of 52,240 pigeons, exclusive of the
military flocks.
Evtry nation In Europe look up the
breeding nnd training of homing pigeon
for use In tlmo of war. Italy followed
next after Franco and Germany In 1876,
At the present time Italy has sixteen
military pigeon lofts. Russia has live
military pigeon lofts. Spain has a mag-
m
nlflcent military pigeon system with
eighteen lofts scattered at advantageous
points throughout tho kingdom; l'or
tugal has fourteen military lofts, Aus
tria seven, Switzerland four, Sweden
and Denmark each have several, HoN
land has no military pigeon lofts, but tho
Government encourages the breeding
and training of homing pigeons, and the
fame of the Dutch pigeons Is world
wide, In Belgium, where pretty much
everybody keeps homing pigeons, Hy
ing them in races may be called the
national pastime.
During our own llttlo war with Spain
the homing pigeon rendered Important
service In carrying messages from the
blockading fleet In Cuban waters, Even
Japan has taken to breeding homing
pigeons for military use. Without
doubt some of these pigeons' will see
service In tho Impending campaign In
he Shantung peninsula.
Naturally, after rendering such distin
guished services during the memorable
Siege of tho French capital, the hom
ing pigeon Is especially prized In
France. It was Inspiration rather than
forethought that placed tho pigeons nt
tho service of the Government In 1871.
At that time thero were no military pig
eons, either In Franco or elsewhere. But
some citizens of Paris by the merest
chanco had some pigeons, and It
occurred to them that they might
bo utilized. They wero offered to
tho Government and promptly nc
cepted. it was six years after
tho war beforo France set nbout the or
ganization of a military pigeon system,
Now thero are twenty-eight military
ions, cnieuy aiong wo eastern boundary.
In the vicinity of tho present conflict,
with about a hundred birds stationed nt
each, besides ten thousand In Paris.
Throughout Franco thero are a hundred
thousand homing pigeons In the hands
of private owners which tho Govern
ment Is empowered by law to com
mandecr In caso of need.
Tho breeding nnd training of tho
pigeons nro under tho care of tho En
glneer Corps. Tho utmost enre. to say
nothing of affection, Is lavished on tho
birds by tho soldiers, who become very
fond of their feathered comrades, Tho
pigeon houses nro placed facing tho
northeast, -which Is opposite tho direc
tion from which tho worst rains come.
Tho averngo llock consists of about a
hundred birds, each of which receives
daily rations of an ounce and a half of
peas, beans and vetches, divided Into
three meals, with unimited mortar, salt
sand and oyster shells to aid In digestion
As soon as they can lly, which Is when
they aro about live weckB old, their
training begins, to routlnuo throughout
their useful life, which averages about
fifteen years, Great care Is taken to
prevent them from perching on any
thing when they aro taken out for their
first flights, Those that do alight on
neighboring roofs or trees are shot with
out mercy. The command to lly la given
in
by shouting or clapping tho hanJs,
signal to return Is a whistle.
As soon as tho young pigeons l
acquired confidence In their wings i
nre taken a couple of kilometers fr -i,
homo and released. The dlstatn e
Increased dally to 300 kltume.i
on tho thirty-fourth day. After t...
pigeon Is fully trained, so that i
can find its way homo from any pu.nt
of tho compass from a distance
300 kilometers, It Is exercised da
morning and afternoon, except wl n
thero Is rain, snow or fog. Cur
records aro kept of each bird's p. -formancc.
Celluloid bands giving
bird's number, corps to which attai I
and Its home loft arc attached t
leg.
Despatches are written on str.p
papcr three Inches wide by four at.
half Inches long, triply folded anl
rolled, or else they arc photograp i
from manuscript on films two i
long by an Inch and a half wide.
the French army two methods of
tachlng tho message to the pigeon
used. In one a goosequllt nn Inch a
a half long la slipped over one -.f
tall feathers, then the message
sorted and held In place by a
wooden plug. Tho other method
attach a tiny aluminum cylinder r -mining
the message to one leg.
maintain that the best way Is to u.--
strip of very thin strong papf-r
Inches long by three-fourths of an
wide, which Is simply rolled about i
leg and held In place by a rubber bar l
When a message Is attached to a
feather so as to annoy the bird he
likely to alight and pull the fej".
with Its message out and then go nn
Any ordinary homing pigeon can Sc
rolled upon to cover a flight of 2.n
miles In five to seven hours. A few
can make 500 to 600 miles. Some of
the finest records have been made b
American birds. One of these remark
able birds, named Nym, owned by J R
Husson of Cresson, Pa., made the flight
of 243 miles between New York and
Its home town In 237 minutes n 1'
which figures out at the rate of a milo
in 53'4 seconds. The fastest trains
make the run of ninety miles between
New York nnd Philadelphia in i
hours, at an average speed of fnrty
flve miles an hour. Two railroads run
out the time between New York a- I
Chicago to twenty hours, the dlstanc
In one instance being 912 miles, in
another 948 miles, which also is sub
stantially forty-five miles an hour.
The average speed of these trains w:i
maintained by Francisco, a h.imln,
pigeon owned by L. Walfelcar of H -boken
in 1879 for the distance of 37'.
miles br.ween Steubenvllle, Ohio, an I
New York. Indeed, Francisco did i
trifle better, for he covered the distant
In eight hours and eight minutes.
course the speed Is much less than tha
madet by Nym, but the distance wn
greater and tho wind, which serloush
affects a pigeon, not so favorable.
Another famous flight was made b
Ned Damon, owned by T. F. Goldman
of Brooklyn In 18S3. Ned covered th
distance of 508 miles from Abingdon.
Va.. In 14 hours and 25 minutes, whlc
was an average of a little more than
thirty-five miles an hour.
Atlanta, owned by Samuel Hunt
Fall River. Mass., made the flight fr -m
Jonesboro, Tenn., to his master's horn,
n distance of 715 miles. In nine days In
1S85. The longest flight recorded for
homing pigeon was from Montgomery.
Ala., .to Fall River, 1,040 miles, made In
1S85 by Alabama, also owned by Mr
Hunt. Alabama was twenty days on
tho road.
The marvellous feature of the flight i
not that It was made In twemy da
but the Intelligence that enabled tli
bird to And Its way homo at all. Th.
almost supernatural Intelligence of tb
homing pigeon has Interested sclen:!- -for
years. All sorts of theories h.n
been advanced to account for It. T!-'
latest theory Is that of a French sa.m
who afttr long and elaborate study, o'
servatlon and experiments, has sue
cecded In convincing himself, at lea
that the homing pigeon Is guided so'..
by Its wonderful vision. This explau -tlon
may answer in the case of plge
elaborately trained over gradually I
creasing distances for nearly tho range
of their flight, but it falls utterly
Alabama's case, This pigeon never
more -than an Inconsiderable fraction
his route near his homo before h-
turned loose at Montgomery to find
way over a strange country for m
than a thousand miles. Balloon.
havo found that their range of
is Increased to a remarkable degre. ,i
high altitudes, but no one will ven" i
to maintain that Alabama could st-
thousand miles.
Tho most reasonable explanation
that made by a French scientist w
after a series of experiments conis:
of 'tho elimination or deadening of
senses of sight, hearing and smell,
elded that the pigeon depends upon t.n
latter sense. Pigeons blindfolded an
their cars closed with wax found tin
way home. But closing their nojt:
with tvnx rendered them helpless o--for
short distances. His explanat.o
was that each locality has Its indli.du.
odor and tho pigeon, by circling up
gets Into an air current bearing the
and follows it home.
Homing pigeons have made s mi.
terestlng altltudo records too, notw.
standing the fact 'that the raivtl.-d
mosphero nt great heistn r.-n l
flight dllllcult. During a Kill.'.-n a
by Gay-Lussac In 1S50 homing pin
wero released at an nltltude 20""
feet. They fell heavily until tie
reached denser nlr, but 'then tl
straight home. Other pigeons thr
out from balloons nt high altitudes h.i"
been froztu to death In then- ii
through tho cold rare air and fell 1
stones 'to 'tho earth, Leo Steven",
American aeronaut, has released h
Ing pigeons at an altitude of n
feet and 200 miles from their Km
They nil returned safely.
The homing pigeon upon bcinn
leased Invariably circles upward t
great height until It gets Its beaihu
then strikes a bee line for h mi
Stevens's pigeons, recognizing tha 1'
000 feet was quite high enough for a
practical purposes, never circled a cir.
but In each Instance simply Hew to t
top of the balloon, where they sat calm,
down until they got their beatings, t'-'
spread their wings and hiked for h
Does this Incident not support the el
that the homing pigeon Is pso-'t
remarkable Intelligence?
t.y,</text>
      </result>
       <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1915-02-07/ed-1/?sp=40&amp;q=pigeon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PIGEONS
FOI? UE.NJ-HE-FBENCHf)BMY.
THOUGH -ulreless telegraphy and aero
planes may have lessened the Im
portance of pigeons as dispatch
bearers In times of war. they have
by no means ousted them. Only recently
two pigeon-dealers, one of them a Ger
man, were arrested in London for bavins
Id their possession sixty "carrier and
other pigeons" In contravention of the
Aliens Restrictions Act; and about the
same time a German spy was arrested th
Belgium with pigeons In his possession
under suspicious circumstances. He was
found ostensibly fishing by the banks of
the Heuse, and sitting on a basket. When
asked what luck he had, he replied,
"None, the beggars won't bite." Just
then, unfortunately for him, "unmistakable
sounds of "cooing" came from the basket.
What happened to him may easily be
Imagined. The pigeons are said to have
been "fairly tender!"
That these aerial messengers are still
.capable of rendering valuable service,
chiefly between forts, is shown by the
fact that in Germany there are about
300,000 of these "homing pigeons" be
longing to various societies, and of this
number about 8,000 are reserved exclu
sively for government use. French statis
tics show that something like 15,000 of
these birds are kept well trained for
military service.
During the Franco-German War of
1870-71 these pigeons played a very im
portant part. At first they carried dls-
patches reduced by photography to micro-
scoplc proportions on thin sheets of paper.
Later, all matter, whether public dis
patches or letters, was printed in ordi

The term "carrier pigeons" for these
birds Is now a misnomer; for the "car
rier" pigeon is a bird of a different type,
distinguished by the enormous develop
ment of the "wattles" round the eyes and
beak. The true "carrier" pigeon is now
more correctljknown as the homing
pigeon, homer, or Antwerp carrier. The
latter name Indicates the origin of the
breed; for the Belgians are without rivals
for their admiration for this bird and
their skill In training it. The iomer is,
even In his native land, represented by
several races, all of which, however, pos
sess the "homing" instinct. These races,
"Les Pigeons Voyageurs," are bred first
and foremost for their powers of flight;
color and marking are of no account.
Where these factors have been taken
into consideration for the ends of the
"show-bench," the flying qualities have
invariably been lost.-</text>
      </result>
       <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045389/1914-11-29/ed-1/?sp=38&amp;q=pigeon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>How War Has Turned Pigeons Into Photographers.
Thuuuh wireless telegraphy
and aeroplanes may have les
sened the Importance of
pigeons as dispatch-bearers in times
of war, they have by no means
ousted them Only a few days since
two pigeon dealers., one of them a
German, were prrested m London
for having in their possession sixty
"carrier and other pigeons" in con
travention of the Aliens Restriction
Act. and about the same time a Ger
man spy was arrested in Belgium
with pigeons In his possession under
circumstances which left no room
for doubt thai they were to be
used to further his nefarious ends.
Now that armies actually can
make use of trained pigeons as pho
tographers. these birds are in the
way of becoming important factors
In war A miniature Camera Is now
manufactured for this purpose. Sus
pended by straps beneath the bird's
breast, its lens is directed downward
while the flight continues, its ac
tion is, of course, automatic, gov
erned by a turning mechanism
which causes a roll of film to be ex
posed at regular internals.
The pieoon photographer flying
abovp the enemy's lines in daytime
brings home on a tiny roll of Aim a
picture record of all that was be
neath' its flight?details of the ene
my's position and strength in men
and guns
The possibilities of pigeon photog
raphy in war were recognized in
Germany some time ago. Experi
ments were made under army super
vision They were successful, views
of parks, rivers and bridges and city
streets of quite remarkable distinct
ness being developed from the ex
posed portions of fllm-rolls brought
back by the pigeon camera-carriers.
That these aerial messengers are
still capable of rendering valuable
service, chiefly between forta, Is
shown by the fact that in Germany
there are about 300,000 of these
"homing pigeons," belonging to va
rious societies, and of thla number
about 8,000 aro reserved exclusively y
for Government uga.
during the Franco-German-War of
1870-71 these pigeons played a very
Important part. At first they carried
dispatches reduced by photography
to microscopic proportions on thin
sheets of paper Later, all matter,
whether public dispatches or letters,
were printed In ordinary type trans
ferred and reduced by mtcro-photog
raphy 'o thin films of collodion mean*
uring at?out two Inches by one.
These wore so light that thousands
of dispatches, weighing less than
one gramme, could bo carried by one
pigeon
The films were rolled up and
placed in a quill, which was then
fastened lengthwise to one of the
tail feathers. Arriving in Paris, the
ntn was flattened out, and tho
printed mutter was thrown on a
screen by lantern and copied
Later sensitive paper replaced tho
screen, so that the labor of copying
was saved The cost of sending mes
sages was high, as may be Judged
from the fact that tne postal fees
on a single dispatch would often
amount to more than $500,000. Each
dispatch was repeated, sometimes
twenty or thirty times, till acknowl
edged by balloon post, which brought
back the birds for anotner Journey.
The Gormans' spared no effort to
fruBtrat these sources of informa
tion. Krhpp made special guns to
bring down (he balloons, and the
pigeons were harassed by trained
falcons.
The term "carrier ptgpons" for
these birds is now a misnomer, for
the "carrier" pigeon Is a bird of a
different type- distinguiBned by the
enormous development or the "wat
tles" round the eyes and beak. The
true "carrier" pigeon Is now more
correctly Known as the homing
pigeon, homer, or Antwerp carrier
The latter name indicates the origin
of the breed, for the Belgians are
without rivalR for their admiration
for this bird and their skill in train
ing it The home' ;h even in his na
tive land, represented .by several
races, all of whtch however, possess
the "homing" instinct. Those races,
"Les Pigeons Voyageurs," are bred
first and foremost for their powers
of flight, color and marKlng are of
no account.
The speod of some of these birds
averaged 1,250 yards a minute, but to
day this has been Increased to 1.83G
yards a minute. The speed, of course,
depends much on tho state of the
weather, In a race between Montar
giB.and Brussels, In_J876, in bright,
clear weather, all the prize-winnera
made the Journey of 270 miles in
three hours and a quarter. Over the
samo course in i$77&gt; in thick, stormy
weather, thirty hours elapsed before
the first bird arrived.
Tiiat the homing pigeon possesses
an extrairdinarily acute sdnse of di
rection ti be no question. A
ease is on of a bird bought tn
Brussels and breMght over to Eng
land. where it remained in close con
finement for several months. Then,
one line day,' It was liberated for ex
ercise. It at once made off, and in
a few hours was back in its toft in,
Brussels, having travelled over 400
miles of country which it had never
seen before. As a rule, however,
these birds are carefully trained, the
initial stages beginning at the age
of about four months. By the end
of the first year a flight of one hun
dred miles can be successfully per*
formed. But longer flights are per-*
formed only by fully matured \rfrds.
of at least three years old. It is a
mistake, however, to suppose, as
some do. that they will fly at night
or in a fog. They roust always have
a clear view,.</text>
      </result>
       <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1912-07-20/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=Pigeon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CARRIER PIGEONS HAVE BECOME PHOTOGRAPHERS
IDFidHANKS
NOWADAYS, since there are so
many means of sending' mes
sages from one person* to an
other, pigeons, which used to have con
siderable work to do as messenger
boys, have been extremely idle and
have largely devoted themselves to
sauntering about in the air and adding
to the beauty of the landscape. But re
cently It has been found that there are
other ways of employing these birds on
Important missions besides sending
them on long distance flights as mes
senger boys. The particular new field
for pigeon activities which has been
discovered is that of photography.
These pigeon photographers were
first started on their mission in life in
Germany, where a physician had been
in the habit of sending carrier pigeons
from his office in the city to a sana
torium in the nearby country. Medicine,
pills and powders were put in a little
satchel and tied to one of the pigeons,
which carried them from the doctor's
office to the sanatorium.
At last one day a pigeon with a very
Important message was despatched
from the sanatorium to the doctor's
office, and although the bird was cele
brated for Its speed and trustworthiness
it did not appear at the end of Its
journey for a month. The same thing
later happened to another bird, and the
owners of the pigeons became very
curious to know what had become of
them. Finally it occurred to some one
that since the pigeons are able to carry
one-third of their weight it would be
possible to attach small cameras to
the birds so that when they wandered
away they would return with a record
of their wanderings on the plate of the
camera.
A special camera was made, acting
automatically, so that it would take a
picture at fixed moments. The pictures
so taken were not more than half an
inch square. For a great many years
different men experimented with these
cameras until they finally invented
something that was entirely practical.
The cameras are attached to the
breast of by straps which
pass under the wings and hold a metal
plate directly between the wings in
place. This plate has two metal hooks
on which the camera fits «o securely
that there is no danger of its being
dislodged even In flight.
The cameras weigh two and a half
ounces or less, and their size varies
never being more than two and a half
by two and a half by four laches. There
are many different sorts of cameras
some of which take panoramic views,
perpendicular and horizontal views and
other repeating cameras, besides the
more common single lens camera.
In order that the picture which the
pigeon is to take may be of any par
ticular place it Is necessary to know
exactly how far tho place is from the
point at which the pigeon is started.
Then the camera apparatus is timed
according to the rate of flight of a car
rier pigeon, so that the shutter will be
open at exactly that point and not any
earlier or later.
One way In which this is done is to
havo a small ball of rubber attached to
the mechanism which holds the shutter
In place. This ball is blown up before
the pigeon is started, so that before it
collapses the picture will be taken. The
ball Is marked with the different places
to which It must be blown up in order
that It may collapse at the proper mFor In
stance, If the operator knows that the
place which he wants the pigeon to
photograph is ten minutes away ac
cording to the pigeon's rate of flying,
the ball is blown up to the ten mlnnte
mark, which is made possible by the
nature of the apparatus. The air es
capes through a small hole in the ball
until just at the proper moment It is
all out of the ball and the shutter opens
so that the photograph is taken.
Of course the pigeon, just like human
beings, is not at all grateful when this
new burden is first placed upon it, and
It struggles hard for a while to rid itself of its queer harness. But when
It finds this Impossible at last it settles
down to carrying Its little camera
faithfully, snd after a few weeks* train
ing It Is apparently quite as comfort
able with It as without it No one
knows what will be the final use to
which the work of these pigeon pho
tographers will be put, but in Germany
they are hoping 'that some use, will
Anally be made of them by the war de
partment, which may send out the
pigeons to take photographs of the de
fences of the enemy or the country over
which it Is desired that a body of
troops shall be sent.</text>
      </result>
        <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84037526/1939-11-15/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=war+pigeons</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PIGEONS ON WINGS OF GOLD
Help Us Fight I'he Enemy
By Ker Robertson
Britain’s ‘'birds with the wings of
gold arein trainiog to all the allieg to
victory. The cream of the homing pig
eon breed have been recruited for the
Royal Air Force.
In the last war pigeons maintained a
valuable line of defence, carrying mes
sages, from the front lines to divisional
headquarters when telephonic communi
cations broke down.
Even io these davs of field radio pig
eons bave their uses, this time with the
RA D
There are meore than 1,000,000 racing
pigeons in acotland, about 40,000 fan
ciers most of them in Lanarkshire—
and British clubs offer £500,000 in prize
money every year.
Since the Government touk over pig-
e n 'nfts this “‘industry’’” has come toa
A detel The State has chosen ithe
bird 2 it-waeots asd nee ‘s and paid a
bourty of £5 for ¢ach bird,
Fanciers propkery tiat a new breed
of pigeon, ar presert being developed,
w'll give I ance and ourselves a sirange
pew wWeap n.
I'his breed of pigeon can see in the
dark. Birds of this new breed have a'-
reacdly accomplished short flights sye
cessfully.
fizeon breedinz doesn’t riquire any
special qualifications or knowledge,
Many newcomers to the game bave coop
ed the priz:s with birds which cost them
cnly five ehillings! And priz s for a sin
gle race are often more than £IOO,
Scientists have yet to discover the ge
cret of the pigeon’s homing instinet.
Most fanciers will tel you birds find
their way home by using their eyes, but
they can’t expolain how birds released
hundreds of miies from their lofts find
their way bome over strange couontry.
Instinct and a stroog pair of wings
are all these birds bave got. Their lo
telligence is practically nil.
A faocier who sends off a bird for a
race must be sure not o alter his house,
his garden, the loft or his clothes in any
wasy. The bird often can’t recognise its
owner’s house if Mrs. Owner hag
chanzed the curtains in its ahsepce!
Birds bave been known to fly off into
the void if their owners awaited them at
the end of a race dressed in strange
clothes!
But the pigeons have qualities which
more shan make up for their lack of in
telligence. Their strength and indomi
table spirit saved maoy lives in the last
war,
The story is told of an advance post of
Scots trorps being iso'ated from their
comrades. Their officers gave the small
band ap for lost; twelve bours later a
carrier pigeon dragged itself into its loft
twelve hours later a carrier pigeon
dragged itself into its loft tweaty miles
behiod the lines.
The message it carried enabled troops
to be rushed up to relieve the outpost,
which had held its ground in face of
very heavy enemy fire,
That pigeon was discovered to have
walked most of the way home from the
gun-riddied outpost with a bullet hole in
one wing clotted with mud. It died
twenty minutes after reaching its loft.</text>
      </result>
        <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1941-09-28/ed-1/?sp=92&amp;q=war+pigeons</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Takeoff: A carrier pigeon it
released from a British plane
Birds Against Hitler
Bomb· may knock oui phone and radio, but
Britain can always count on her valiant
last-ditch couriers—the war pigeons
by C. Patrick Thompson
The air shook. Over by the wood
a fortified cottage and part of the
hillside roee in the air and
sprayed the landscape. Two khaki,
red-tabbed officers on the slope below
involuntarily ducked, but kept their
binoculars leveled. On the hillside,
phone, wire and radio were disrupted
by the blast. Wings weren't, though
wings of the war pigeons. And those
were what the officers were watching
for.
They came two blue-gray birds
fluttering high out of the drifting,
bitter smoke. The two men watched
with tense anxiety. It was one thing
for the pigeons to escape at all. Quite
another for them to emerge function
ing on all cylinders.
"They're on their way," said one
officer. "They ought to be making
fifty, with this breeze on their tails."
The other, glancing at his wrist
watch, agreed. "They shouldn't be
later than two-twenty," he said.
their own requests for pigeons to do a
job which no one and nothing else
can do.
The war pigeon of today has learned
tricks that would have surprised
Decimus Junius Brutus, the first cap
tain to harness homing pigeons to his
war chariot, flying them with messages
to relief legions over the heads of
Mark Antony's besieging force. After
1870, when the beleaguered Parisians
flew pigeons over the Prussians' heads
in the same old way, men thought that
the inventions of Bell, Marconi and
Morse would combine to put war
pigeons out of business. But World
War No. 1 proved them wrong. By the
time the Armistice was signed, the
British army alone had 22,000 pigeons,
150 mobile lofts, and 400 soldier
pigeoneers, while tlie A. E. F. Signal
Service, starting in 1917 with only 14
pigeon men, finished with 6,000 birds,
50 lofts and 324 men.
Not Qaught Short
The British demobilized their pigeon
service after the war. If it had not
been for the sport of pigeon racing,
carried on by 70.000 fanciers in the
British isles, the present array would
have been caught shorter of pigeons
than it was of tanks and warplanes.
And this would have been a tragic
situation, for despite enormous ad
vance in war methods, science has yet
to find a substitute for the homing
pigeon, the last-ditch fighter in the
battle of communications.
That is not so surprising when you
closely inspect a homing pigeon, with
his bright eyes and deep chest and
powerful wings. When you study
pigeon performances under various
weather conditions and bend an ear to
pigeoneers talking of their pigeons as
racing men talk of blood horses. When
you begin to understand that vital
quality which keeps a homing pigeon
battling as long as his strong heart
pumps blood.
A pigeon, trained, fit and bred of
good, stout stock, ran fly 500 miles in
24 hours at an average of 40 miles an
hour. He will make a night halt, and
λ wciivj-uTt mu» awa;, lire
circled over the mobile loft that was
their home. They popped through the
trap, with thoughts of maple peas and
corn maybe a slug of hemp seed as
a reward for special work. The loft
bell rang. A hand reached in, deftly
picked the birds and detached the slim
little bakelite capsule from their ankle
rings. Then their official time was
recorded on the books a flying speed
of 51.4 miles an hour.
A Cog Got to Work
Thus another cog in the enormous
and integrated machine of Britain's
defense system dropped neatly into
place. The performance of these birds
had been tested under a careful imita
tion of battle conditions. A remote
strong point had been blown up, its
communications and defenders anni
hilated. But the pigeons had escaped
to carry the tale back to headquarters
at a speed of nearly a mile a minute.
This is only the latest chapter added
to the whole war-pigeon story, which
is assuming ever-increasing impor
tance as British tanks and warplanes
multiply, and special services put in
Home again: Soldi·» receive the airman's message
hUtêt Camtlme
he may pause for a sip of water. But
a seed sandwich won't tempt him
he's too eager to get back to the home
table, and his people. Storms will slow
but not stop him.
Recently one red-checkered hen of
the R. A. F. pigeon service won die
patch mention by flying fast through
a heavy thunderstorm in a high wind,
bringing first news of a British bomb
er's forced landing. Another, a blue
checkered cock, released in a heavy
storm 22 mile· from its loft at 6:44 A.M.,
with a report of the result of a fight
with swastika aircraft, homed at
7 jOO a.m. A third, released in Norway,
flew back through a blizzard to his loft
in Scotland. It took him two days to
make it.
Although they fly by landmarks,
pigeons have been known to find their
way through dark night, dense fog and
heavy mist. One cock, liberated 160
miles out at sea on a foggy night, rang
the bell at his home in very good time.
A black-checkered cock, put aboard a
reconnaissance machine of the R. A. P.
coastal command, arrived home with
this message "Landed, engine trouble.
Taxiing home. Send motor launch
getting worse.". The pigeon had flown
through thick mist with that message
on his leg.</text>
      </result>
        <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89053204/1919-06-01/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=war+pigeons</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>English War Pigeons
Being Demobilized
LONDON. —'(Correspondence of The
Associated Press.) —Demobilization of
i English war pigeons and men who
care for them in France has taken
I place, with the exception of birds and
men selected for the Army of Occu
pation. About 10,000 birds that had
served their country faithfully were
sold in France and Belgium anproceeds of sale divided among char
itable institutions of those countries
and England in accordance with the
wish of the breeders who had donated
i the pigeons to the British army.
Many a man owes his life to the
rapid flight of a pigeon from a broken
down seaplane. In the battle of Mes
sines 1,200 pigeons were used to carry
messages, not a single one of which
went astray.
The German pigeon service was
very thorough. A Birmingham medal
1 maker imitated so perfectly a message
j container used by the enemy that it
was possible to send a number of
“dud" messages to German lofts with
their own captured birds.</text>
      </result>
        <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86091128/1920-09-10/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=war+pigeons</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
        <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88063294/1942-01-20/ed-1/?sp=23&amp;q=war+pigeons</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
